片名：关键投票
SWING VOTE
经过一番激烈的竞选角逐之后 美国人今天将会去投票站…
After a hotly contested race, Americans go to the polls today...
相信票选结果将十分接近
in what promises to be a very close election.
共和党的安德鲁・布恩 希望继续留任总统宝座…
The Republican Andrew Boone, hoping to hold on to the Oval Office...
以微弱优势胜出…
by edging out...
民主党的挑战者唐纳德・格林利夫
the Democratic challenger Donald Greenleaf.
巴德…巴德
Bud... Bud.
巴德！
Bud!
我…我给他打回去
I'll call... I'll call him back.
如果我们有电话，你当然会 快起来！
If we had a phone, you could. Come on!
该死！很冷的
Goddamnit! It's cold.
我们又要迟到了，你得去洗个澡
We're gonna be late again. You need a shower.
你竟然穿着衣服睡觉！
Can't believe you slept in your clothes!
有没有给我留点热水？
Leave me any hot water?
我不知道，热水器会自我修复吗？
I don't know. Water heater fix itself?
天，莫莉！你为什么不请一天假呢，啊？
Christ, Molly! Why don't you just take the day off, okay?
我给你写假条
I'll write you a note.
快！我不会再来叫你了！
Now! I'm not going to tell you again!
起床！
Get up!
巴德！
Bud!
好，我起来了！
Alright, I'm coming!
- 是什么？ - 鸡蛋沙拉
- What? - Egg salad.
又吃这个？
Again?
你喜欢鸡蛋沙拉
You like egg salad.
呃，我不是每天都喜欢 你应该稍微换一下
Well, not every damn day I don't. You could mix it up a little.
我们得省着点花
We're on a budget.
你想吃好点？那就喝少点
You wanna eat better? Drink less beer.
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Fine. - Fine.
- 别忘了今天的事儿 - 什么…今天什么事儿？
- And don't forget today. - What's... what's today?
大选，笨蛋！
Election day, dummy!
我要写一份你投票的报告，还记得吗？
I'm supposed to do a report on you voting, remember?
我已经告诉你了，我都没去登记
I already told you before I'm not even registered.
我用邮件帮你登记了
I registered for you in the mail.
那太好了，我都可以做陪审员了
That's great, I could get jury duty now.
- 这是你的公民义务 - 我的公民什么？
- It's your civic responsibility. - It's my civic, my what?
这是你的公民义务
It's your civic responsibility.
我的公民义务？你从哪儿学的这些废话？
My civic responsibility? Where you learning this crap?
艾伯拉茜太太
Mrs. Abernathy.
呃，那就离她远点儿
Well, stay away from her.
她是我老师
She's my teacher.
签字
Sign this.
什么东西?
What is it?
问卷调查，我需要问你的政治观点
A questionnaire. I'm supposed to ask you about your politics.
呃，接着说
Well, go ahead.
我已经填好了
I already filled it in.
我是想让你答得聪明点儿
I wanted you to sound smart.
说说第一个问题吧
Give me the first question anyway.
你的政治面貌是什么？
What's your political affiliation?
呃，我是一个立场明确的反对派
Alright, I'm a conscious objector.
这不是战争，巴德 这是大选，你是一个无党派选民
It's not a war, Bud. It's an election. And you are an independent.
无党派？ 为什么我是无党派？
Independent? Why in the hell would I be an independent?
因为两党制度…
Because the two party system...
忽视了贫穷劳动者的需要
has neglected the needs of the working poor.
- 告诉你，宝贝… - 又来了
- Let me tell you something, baby... - Here we go again.
投票他妈的一点用都没有
The voting doesn't count for a goddamn thing.
最多让你觉得你好像有点权利
Just a way to make you feel like you're in control of something.
你给谁投一点都不重要 我们还是买不起保险…
It doesn't matter who you vote for, we can't afford insurance and...
你要是病了 我还得去卖血
if you get sick, I'm gonna have to start selling my blood again.
艾伯拉茜太太说每张票都有用 这是社会契约
Mrs. Abernathy said every vote counts. It's a social contract.
社会契约 这个艾伯拉茜太太就是个猪脑子
It's a social contract. This Mrs. Abernathy is full of shit.
下班后在投票站见
Meet me at the polling place after work.
行
Fine.
你忘了什么事儿吧？
You forgetting something?
巴德，这次要是搞砸了 我就不跟你了
Bud, screw this up and I'm leaving you.
表现好点！
Do good!
那个…
Where...
杜维跑哪儿去了？
Where the hell is Dewey?
他被解雇了
He got laid off.
胡说！他被内雇了
Bullshit! He got insourced.
内雇？
Insourced?
内雇，不是把我们的活儿弄去墨西哥…
Insourced. Instead of exporting our jobs to Mexico...
而是把墨西哥人弄来干我们的活儿
they're importing Mexicans to take our jobs.
你就是个傻子，知道吗？
You're paranoid, you know that?
注意！今天早上的例会正式取消
Attention! The opening this morning is officially cancelled.
我他妈的连这儿的标签都快不认得了！
I can't even read the damn signs no more!
我们在这儿的日子不多了 记住我的话吧！
Our days are numbered, fellas. You mark my words!
这些家伙为了一半儿的钱能干两倍的活儿
These hombres work twice as hard for half the money.
我倒发现他们比我们更需要这份工作！
I just figure they need this job twice as bad as us!
你到底是哪一边的？
Whose side are you on?
我哪边都不是，洛威尔 我只是说些明摆着的事实
I don't take sides, Lowell. Just stating the obvious.
下一步，他们连我们的投票权也要抢了
Next thing, they'll be taking away our right to vote.
你去投票吗，巴德？
You voting, Bud?
这是社会契约，不是吗？
It's a social contract, isn't it?
那你要投给谁？
Who are you voting for?
鬼才知道！
Shit if I know!
看起来我的牙白多了 像是到第八格了
I think I picked up a couple shades. Looks like an eight.
你觉得呢， 马蒂？
What do you think, Marty?
佛罗尼达的进展我不满意
I don't like the margin in Florida.
给我车一些年轻的共和党人 去棕榈海滩的投票站
Bus some young Republicans down to the polling stations in Palm Beach.
要高个子的金发男人
Make sure they're tall, they're blonde and they're men.
为什么？ 因为年纪大的犹太人看见一群激进的白种年轻人…
Because old Jews see a pack of angry young white males...
他们会重新考虑要不要下车！
and they're gonna think twice about getting out of their car!
肯尼迪是九号色，他把人类送上了月球
Kennedy was a nine. And he put a man on the moon.
我们就是要这种 可以用来炫耀的亮点
That's what we need. Something to shoot for.
一个意义重大的时刻 就像…我也不知道
A defining moment. Like... I don't know.
战胜癌症
Cure for cancer.
俄亥俄州允许同性恋结婚 每20分钟广告一次
Ohio run the gay marriage ad every twenty minutes.
我还不信我们搞不定这几个 连上帝都看着不顺的人了
Let's see if we can't get those God fearing bastards off the fence.
我们弄一批科学家 把他们送进沙漠
We take a bunch of scientists, put them in the desert somewhere.
就像曼哈顿计划一样 你在听我说吗？我是认真的
Like the Manhattan project. Are you listening to me? I'm serious about this.
我想在一届任期内癌症还是比较难啃的 先生
I think that cancer is going to be a tough nut to crack in one term, sir.
那么，我们弄一个十年规划
So, we make it a ten year plan.
- 林肯看到奴隶制的终结吗？ - 没有
- Lincoln got to see the end of slavery? - No.
- 肯尼迪看到登月的成功吗？ -  没有
- Did Kennedy get to see the moon shot? - Nope.
没有！但是他们都赢得了声誉！ 理想才是重要的
No! But they got the credit! It's the idea that counts.
只有制定目标的人才被载入史册！
The guy that sets the goal gets in the history books!
希望和乐观！ 马蒂，美国人民需要一个…
Hope and positivity! Marty, the American people want a bright...
灿烂的笑容来代表这个国家的未来
shining smile to represent the promise of this country.
看看华盛顿
Take old Georgie there.
天，他真了不起
Boy, he was off the charts.
他们曾想尊他为王
They wanted to make him King.
士兵们！
Son of a gun!
谢谢，谢谢你们的到来
Thank you, thank you for coming.
葛琳娜和我想要感谢美国…
Galena and I would like to thank America...
给予我这个光荣的机会
for this glorious opportunity.
我见过各种民族，肤色和信仰的人…
I have met people of every race, color and creed...
在这么长时间的竞选活动当中
during this long campaign.
我向你们保证我的白宫 将会是一个多彩之家
I pledge to you that my White House will be a rainbow house.
它将对各种肤色和各种信仰的人开放
It'll be open to people of all colors and creeds.
现在，请投我一票吧 我们需要你们的支持
Now, please, go and vote. We need your support.
太棒了，媒体那边我去办
That was great. I'm gonna go do press.
好
Great.
格林利夫！格林利夫！
Greenleaf! Greenleaf!
盖洛普调查显示你们落后一个百分点
Gallup has you down by a point.
有线新闻和今日美国的民调是领先两个点 福克斯新闻说我们落后六十个点
CNN, USA Today, has us up by two. News has us down by sixty.
今天您要对还未作决定的中间选民说些什么吗？
What message are you trying to get out to the undecideds today?
跟昨天，上周，去年一样…
The same message we put out yesterday, last week and last year...
跟我们刚开始竞选时一样 那也是我们会赢的原因
when we started this campaign and that's why we're going to win.
因为我们才是民众的出路 不是陈词滥调和花言巧语
Because we have the answers. Not platitudes and jingoistic rhetoric.
这才是真理 是真才实干
This is the truth train operation real deal.
最近，总统在广播宣传中称格林利夫…
In recent days, the president has aired ads claiming Greenleaf...
曾在一个裸体主义者聚集地度假
has vacationed at a nudist colony.
嗨，听着，那是无聊的指控，纯粹是瞎编
Come on, now, that's a tired accusation. It's pure fiction.
- 那么，你如何解释那些照片？ - 右翼势力的诽谤，这就是原因
- Then, how do you answer for the photos? - Right wing blogo-smear, that's how.
我也可以站在这里乱传谣言说…
I could stand here and perpetuate the rumor that as a young man...
总统年轻的时候烂赌上瘾 但是我才不会自降身份跟他们一样
the president had a gambling addiction, but I'm got going to sink to their level.
不顾事实信口胡说
Despite eye witness accounts and documentation.
他们散布谣言，我们传播理想
They sling mud, we sling ideas.
但是，如果格林利夫输了 你将在政治舞台上大放异彩了
Still, if Greenleaf loses, you'll be 0 for 7 on the national scene.
谢谢， 贝蒂，抱歉 采访到此为止
Thank you, Betty. Sorry, folks, that's all I have time for.
寄生虫！
Leeches!
为什么投票很重要
Why it's important to vote.
很多勇敢的战士牺牲生命
Many brave soldiers sacrificed themselves.
我们理所应得的权利
A right we take for granted.
- 为民权 - 为民治
- For the people. - By the people.
我们是民众！
We the people!
我读不出来了
I can't read my writing.
世界上所有伟大的文明都遵循同样的规律
All the world's great civilizations have followed the same path.
从被奴役到自由 从自由到富裕…
From bondage, to liberty, from liberty to abundance...
从富裕到自满 从自满到冷漠…
from abundance to complacency. From complacency to apathy...
从冷漠再回到被奴役
from apathy back to bondage.
如果我们不想被历史所左右 我们就必须打破这个怪圈
If we're to be the exception to history, then we must break the cycle.
因为人一旦忘却历史 就注定将重蹈覆辙
For those who do not remember the past are condemned to repeat it.
非常好，孩子们 非常好
Very good, everybody. Very good.
拿着
Hold this.
好，记着，不到操场不要跑
Okay, remember, no running till you get out to the playground.
你的最后一个学生太棒了 我想用在我的新闻里
Your last one was great. I'd like to use it on the news.
- 莫莉？ - 是的
- Molly? - Yes.
莫莉，过来
Molly, come here.
这是麦迪逊小姐 她是新闻记者
This is Ms. Madison. She's the reporter from the news.
- 嗨，莫莉 - 嗨
- Hi, Molly. - Hi.
- 你好吗？ - 很好
- How you doing? - Good.
你的作文很有想法
Your essay was very thoughtful.
谢谢
Thanks.
麦迪逊小姐想在今晚播出你的作文
Ms. Madison is going to show your essay tonight.
- 是不是很高兴？ - 是的，夫人
- Isn't that exciting? - Yes, madam.
告诉我 长大以后想干什么？
Tell me something. What do you want to be when you grow up?
我思前想后 要么做个兽医，要么去当美联储主席
I go back and forth. Either a veterinarian or chairman of the Fed.
巴德去哪儿了？
Where's Bud?
半小时前他去厕所了 我听见喇叭里在喊他的名字
Went to take a leak half an hour ago. I heard his name over the loudspeaker.
你中午吃什么？
What'd you have for lunch?
- 鸡蛋沙拉，你呢？ - 熟鸡蛋
- Egg salad. You? - Hard boiled.
嗨，巴德
Hey, Bud.
只想给你提个醒儿
Just giving you a heads up.
管理层希望我们再裁10％的人
Management wants us to cut another ten percent.
呃，你是管理层啊，卡尔
Well, you are management, Carl.
你看，六个月你都没准时上过班
Look, you haven't punched in on time in six months.
呃，我偶尔晚了五分钟 有什么大不了的？
So, I'm five minutes late every once in a while. What is the big whoop?
今年你请了三十一天的病假，巴德
You took thirty-one sick days this year, Bud.
呃，我有孩子， 卡尔 她把学校里的病传给我了
Well, I gotta kid, Carl. She brings it home from school.
我操！妈的！
Shit! Goddamnit!
呃，真是的，卡尔！
Well, hell, Carl!
你一进来就直接播录像就行了
You could have showed me your footage when you walked in.
我们一起上的学，巴德 我一直都觉得你不错
I know we went to school together, Bud. I've always liked you.
你得给我一个让你留下的理由
You gotta give me one good reason why I should keep you.
为什么留下你
Why I can keep you.
一群废物！
All hellsabelle!
抱歉听说你丢了工作
Sorry you lost your job.
没事儿，亨利，只是…
That's alright, Henry. Just...
只要赢了你的钱 我就从被炒变成退休了
As soon as take your money, I'm going from fired to retired.
- 嗨，巴德！ - 怎么？
- Hey, Bud! - Yes?
莫莉在电视上！
Molly is on TV!
- 从冷漠再回到被奴役 - 老天！
- Apathy back to bondage. - Geez!
如果我们不想被历史所左右 我们就必须打破这个怪圈
If we are to be the exception to history, then we must break the cycle.
- 克里，几点了？ - 七点过九分
- Curly, what time you got? - Nine past seven.
天哪！
God!
我的天哪！该死！
God, man! Shit!
该死！
Goddamnit!
请插入您的选票
PLEASE, INSERT YOUR BALLOT
错误代码 重启
ERROR CODE - RESTART
我把头撞了
I hurt the top of my head.
来吧，躺下
Come on, lay down.
对不起，宝贝
I'm so sorry, baby.
我想和妈妈一起住
I want to live with Mom.
我也想
Me too.
新墨西哥州历来都是决定结果的关键
New Mexico is a classic swing state.
- 请问是麦迪逊太太吗？ - 说
- Mrs. Madison? - Speaking.
我是新墨西哥州竞选处的
I'm calling from the New Mexico election board.
- 什么？ - 新墨西哥州竞选处
- The what? - The New Mexico election board.
夫人 你昨晚有没有在德士古镇投票站投票？
Madam, did you cast your vote at a Texico polling station last night?
我早上投的
I voted in the morning.
早上，好的
In the morning. Alright.
出什么事了吗？
Is there something the matter?
没，没有，抱歉打扰你了
No, no, sorry to bother you.
太令人震惊了 除了新墨西哥州，根据各州的情况...
It is amazing. With every state but New Mexico reporting...
美国总统竞选之争已进入白热化
we're now in a dead heat for the American presidency.
每位候选人几乎得到了同样的票数
Each candidate with virtually the same amount of electoral votes.
270票，获胜的神奇数字 真是精采绝伦！
270, the magic number to win. This is a real photo finish!
谁能在该州赢得普选投票
And it goes to whoever wins the popular vote in the state.
所有五张选举团票都将归于该党
All five electoral college votes then swing to that party.
噢，该州再不是无用的迷人之地了
Well, they don't call it the land of enchantment for nothing.
谁能赢得新墨西哥州 谁就能赢得白宫
Whoever takes New Mexico, takes the White House.
再一次让我们有了似曾相识的感觉 2000年的大选将由达德郡来决定
It's deja vu again. 2000 presidential election came down to Dade County.
总数一亿五百万张选票 由佛罗里达州的四百张来决定输赢
400 votes in the state of Florida, out of a total of 105 million cast.
如果被证明是平局 任何一名候选人都不能赢得多数
If this is a certified tie, neither the candidate would receive the majority.
历史上有过处理这种场面的总统吗？
Do we even have a president to deal with this?
依据第十二次修正案 结果将由众议院来决定
Pursuant to the 12th amendment, the House of Representatives would decide.
自从约翰・昆西・亚当斯在1824年击败安德鲁・杰克逊以来
That hasn't happened since...
还从未发生过
John Quincy Adams defeated Andrew Jackson back in 1824.
那就是说是历史罕见了
We're talking rare.
难道 这不是给全国人民的一次最好的公民教育吗？
No, this isn't a great civics lesson to the people of this country?
如果新墨西哥州有人没有投票的话 他现在肯定很后悔
If anyone in New Mexico didn't vote, he be kicking themselves right now.
最新消息 柯里郡的结果还是很接近分不出胜负
The latest reports coming in, Curry County still too close to call.
这次选举的结果将由一个小郡来决定 这可能吗？
This election is down to a single county. Is this even possible?
听着，约翰 德士古镇只有653名注册选民
Listen, John, there's only 653 registered voters in Texico.
选票他们已经重新数过了
And they've already recounted those votes.
我知道 有这消息再加一美金，我都能买条船了
I know. With that information and a dollar, I could buy a chalupa!
我认识的投了票的人都被打过电话了
Everyone I know who voted has been personally called.
那又怎样？
So what?
所以，选举结果 事实是将由柯里郡来决定…
So, the election. The fact that it's down to Curry County...
这跟德士古镇有关
it has something to do with Texico.
噢，天哪，等会儿打给你！
Oh my God. Call you back!
巴德！
Bud!
快！
Come on!
老天，我的头！
God, my head!
怎么了？现在几点？
What? What time is it?
有人要见你
There's some people here to see you.
有人？
Some people?
看样子是政府的
They look official.
- 儿童福利会的？ - 我猜是的
- Child services? - That's what I'm thinking.
- 好了 - 走吧
- Okay. - Here we go.
约翰逊先生，我们应该先打电话的 但是你没有电话
Mr. Johnson, we would have called first, but you don't have a telephone.
噢，没有，没有，我们有电话的
No, no, no, we got a phone.
只是现在不通了 你看，我会弄好的
It's just not connected right now. But I'm on it, you know.
自从老婆走了以后 不得不说有些困难，但是…
I'm not gonna say it's been easy since the wife left, but...
- 我们过的很好 - 当然
- we're getting on fine. - Sure are.
而且，我会付清这些帐单的，我保证 只要我找到新工作
And I'm gonna pay these off, I swear. Just as soon as I find a new job.
- 新工作？ - 是的
- A new job? - Yes.
我以前是威利・纳尔森乐队的 我在想…
I used to be in this Willy Nelson tribute band. I was thinking about...
等贝司手假释出来以后 再把大伙儿召集起来
getting the guys back together again, soon as our bass player gets paroled.
还有喝酒，我知道 我知道这看起来不好
And the drinking, I know it, I know it looks bad.
戒酒已经是我的头号任务了
And licking that sucker is at the top of my list.
请不要带走我女儿
Please don't take away from me.
你说什么我都可以去做，我发誓
I'll do anything you say, I swear.
她是我的唯一
She's just my only good thing.
约翰逊先生，我们不是社会福利会的
Mr. Johnson, we're not from Social Services.
不是？
No?
我们是州选举管理局的
We're from the State Election Bureau.
他妈的！感谢上帝！
Fuck! Thank you, Jesus!
我是鲍尔秘书长 这位是怀特检察长
I'm Secretary of State Brower. And this is Attorney General Wyatt.
约翰逊先生，你昨晚投票了吗？
Mr. Johnson, did you cast your vote last night?
昨晚，你投票没有？
Last night, did you vote?
是的，那是我的公民义务，不是吗？
That's right, it's my civic duty, isn't it?
当然了
Indeed it is.
约翰逊先生，这是你的签名吗？
Mr. Johnson, is this your signature?
我猜是的
I guess.
你猜这是你签的？
You guess it's your signature?
噢，不，是的 那是我签的
No, no. That's right. That's my signature.
你的存根还在吗？
Did you retain your stub?
什么存根？
What stub?
你的选票上的存根
The perforated stub on top of your ballot.
我给你做作业的存根呢？
Where's that perforated stub that I gave you for your school project?
在我这儿
I've got it.
是他
It's him.
是，是他，你什么意思 ＂他？＂我，他？
Yeah, it's him. What do you mean, "him?" Me, him?
先生，你投的票无效
Sir, your vote didn't count.
约翰逊先生，我们依职权通知你…
Mr. Johnson, it's our duty to inform you...
你有权在规定的时限内重新投票
that you are entitled to recast your ballot in a timely manner.
要是我不想呢？
What if I don't want to?
巴德！
Bud!
那么好吧，能不能 我能不能轻声地口头选投呢？
Alright then, how about if I, how about if I just whisper it to you then?
就在这儿把这事办了 就现在，你也可以听！
Right here we'd get it over with, right now and you can listen too!
不行， 先生，我们有严格的规定和法律程序的
No, sir, there are strict rules and legal procedures.
法律个屁，老兄 我可请不起律师
Legal shit. Shit, fellas, I can't afford a lawyer.
你没犯事，不用请律师
You're not in trouble. You don't need a lawyer.
但是，得进行宣誓
However, I will have to administer an oath.
宣誓？
An oath?
宣誓，请 把手放在圣经上
An oath. Please, place your hand on the Bible.
埃里斯特・约翰逊先生，你是否愿意…
Do you, Earnest Johnson...
发誓依据法律的精神重新投票？
swear to recast your ballot in the spirit of the law?
愿意，行，没问题
Yeah, yes, sure. Okay.
记下来
So noted.
你的请求将会记录在案 我们将会给你安排重新投票的时间
A petition will be filed on your behalf and a date will be set for your revote.
这是不是能让我平步青云？
Does this put me on some sort of fast track list?
就像进陪审团那样？
You know, for like jury duty?
考虑到这件事的重要性，请保守秘密
Considering the gravity of this situation, keep all of this a secret.
晚安
Have a good night.
对不起
Sorry.
你好大的胆子！ 你这一下给我带来多大麻烦！
You should be! I could get into all kinds of trouble because of you!
唉，莫莉！
Gosh, Molly!
你怎么就不能不要多管闲事呢？
Why can't you learn just to let things be?
跟你说了这对我很重要 但是你从来都不听！
I told you this was important to me, but you never listen!
又一个惊人消息 新墨西哥州竞选管理局报告说…
Another astonishing development: New Mexico Elections Bureau is reporting...
该州的票选结果将由一张 非正常选票决定
a single irregular ballot is holding up a final decision in the state.
如我所述，将由一张选票 一票定决，同胞们！
As I said, a single ballot. That's one vote, folks!
真是无奇不有 国家广播环球公司已经获悉这名投票人…
This really couldn't get any stranger, MSNBC has learned that the voter...
已经得到确认 并且同意重新投票
has been identified and has agreed to recast the ballot.
一个选民将决定本州的 5张选举团票的归属
One voter will decide the fate of the state's five electoral votes.
在这不同寻常的一天，没人会忘记 一个美国公民…
On this bizarre day, no one will soon forget, one American citizen...
将直接选出下一届美国总统
will effectively choose the next President of the United States.
很明显那个电子投票机出故障了
Apparently the electronic voting machine malfunctioned.
那张票被扫描录入了 但是还没计数机器就坏了
The ballot was scanned, but the machine died before the vote was counted.
太反常了
It's an anomaly.
别废话，拉里！ 是哪个投票站的机器？
No shit, Larry! What polling station was the machine in?
德士古镇，新墨西哥州，先生
Texico, New Mexico, sir.
有这么个地方吗？
Is that a place?
德士古镇在他妈的哪儿？
Where the hell is Texico?
新墨西哥州，先生，属于柯里郡
New Mexico, sir, Curry County.
新墨西哥州选举法规定 如果投票人的权利受到侵害…
New Mexico election law dictates if a voter's right is violated...
投票人有权重新投票，我知道
The voter shall be-entitled to recast the ballot. I know.
好吧，孩子们，开始战斗吧
Alright, kids, we're going to war.
地图！给我拿张地图来！
A map! Somebody get me a map!
这头蠢猪挡在了我们和白宫之间 给我把他找出来
There's one schmuck standing between us and the White House. Find out who it is.
这么做是违法的
We can't do that legally.
只是把他找出来
Just find him.
今天本来要学习果冻的细胞质的
We were supposed to my cytoplasm out of Jell-O today.
宁愿坐在破烂的教室里，也不愿出来…
What kinda kid would rather sit in a crummy classroom...
有这样的小孩吗？
than be out here?
不去找工作，而坐在这里钓鱼，有这样的老爸吗？
What kind of father goes fishing when he should be looking for a new job?
那种喜欢…
The kind who would just like...
多花一点时间陪他女儿的人
to spend a little more time with his daughter.
就是那种人
That's who.
- 好吧 - 好
- Fine. - Fine.
反正，我一直在想
Anyway, I've been thinking.
真新鲜！
How refreshing!
老天！你能不能不要总是那么聪明？
Jesus! You gotta quit being such a smart ass all the time?
你不要老是拿耶稣当脏话！
And you've got to stop using Jesus as a cuss word all the time!
他可是无数人的救世主
He's a billion people's Savior.
好，行了吧，行不？ 我不说了
Alright, fine, okay? I get it.
- 好吧 - 好
- Fine. - Fine.
我真希望... 你妈能在这里…
I wish... your mom could be here...
跟你讲讲所有发生的事
to talk to you about everything that's going on.
她不肯谈
I really do.
不是，她…不是，她不能
No, she... no, she can't.
她只是，她不能，宝贝
She's just, she can't, baby.
巴德
Bud.
下周二，父亲要去学校
Next Tuesday, is bring your father to school day.
- 怎样？ - 我想你参加
- So? - I want you to come.
我没工作你不感到难堪吗？
It's not gonna embarrass you that I don't have a job?
我不在乎
I don't care.
我只要你来
I want you to come anyway.
- 你能记住吗？ - 当然
- Think you can remember? - Of course.
怎么记？
How?
呃…
Well...
我写在额头上
I'll write it on my forehead.
我能去上学了吗？
Can I go to school, now?
好，让我再钓一杆
Yes. Just one more cast.
去把车发动
Why don't you go start the truck.
争取把我们俩都拍进去，好吗？ 好，走！
Try to get a two shot, alright? Okay, come on!
埃纳斯特・约翰逊！
Earnest Johnson!
- 什么事？ - 我是凯特・麦迪逊
- Yes? - Kate Madison.
- 嗨，你好 - 你好
- Hi, there. - Hi.
老天！你是新闻台的小姐！
Shit! You're the lady from the news.
是的，我想问你几个问题
I am, and I'd like to ask you a few questions.
你知道吗，你比电视上还好看
You know, you're much prettier than you are on the TV.
谢谢，我想…
Thanks. I would...
别误会，你在电视上也很漂亮
Don't get me wrong, you're pretty on the TV too.
只是，我们的电视太旧把你“挤”扁了
Just, we got an old set that kinda "squirshes" you.
看谁都是扁的
Squishes everybody.
我知道了，约翰逊先生，我肯定…
I believe, Mr. Johnson. I believe...
你可以叫我巴德
You can call me Bud.
巴德，我希望你能告诉我为什么那些人…
Bud. I was hoping you could tell me why those men...
深夜从圣达菲飞过来见你
flew from Santa Fe, to see you in the middle of the night.
呃，事实上，我保证过要保密的
Well, actually, I kinda promised to keep that a secret.
你是说，你会去重新投票
You mean, you're going to recast your vote.
呃，他妈的，我猜这根本不是什么秘密了
Well, shit, I guess that I guess it ain't that much of a secret then.
呃，听着，巴德 你需要注意你的用词
Now, listen, Bud, you need to watch your language.
- 我们会放到电视上去的，好吗？ -  用词？
- We're taping this for TV, okay? - The language?
他妈的，噢当然！
Goddamnit, yes of course!
我要问的是，你之前投给了谁 现在是否也一样？
The question now is, who you voted for and are you going to vote the same way?
再提醒我一下谁在竞选？
Remind me again who's running?
那么也就是说，你还没有决定？
What you're saying is, you're keeping an open mind?
是，那个…
Yeah, that's...
我就是那种人
That's the kinda guy I am.
你在开玩笑吧！
You gotta be kidding me!
这是条大新闻，头号新闻！
This is OJ big. Bigger!
我要给联播台打电话！
I gotta call network!
约翰，这个新闻让我来报道
John, let me break the story.
还以为我会一直待在这个鬼地方
I thought I was gonna die in this shithole.
你答应过只要时机合适，会给我机会的 现在时机来了！
You said that when the time was right, you'd give me a chance. That's the time!
我们又要重回新闻市场了
We'll be back to a real market.
这个城市！电梯，中餐馆，犯罪，交通
The city! With elevators and Chinese restaurants and crime and traffic.
我拿到扎克莉女士的最佳母猪获奖录像带了
I got the tape of Mrs. Zachary's prize winning sow.
别管什么扎克莉女士 也别管什么母猪了！
Screw Mrs. Zachary. And screw the sow!
你答应过的
You promised me.
马上给联播台打电话 不许搞砸
Get network on the phone. Don't screw it up.
- 你不会失望的！ - 最好不会！达琳！
- You won't regret it! - Better not! Darlene!
那么…你爸爸会来讲话吗？
So... is your dad coming to talk to our class?
我不知道 自从我妈走后他就没出过门
I don't know. Doesn't really leave the house much since my mom left.
我妈也走了
Mine left too.
她去阿尔伯克基寻她的歌星梦去了
She's pursuing a singing career in Albuquerque.
她成了大明星后我就搬去跟她住
I'm going to move there when she becomes a big star.
她会带我去巡回演出，给我任何东西
And she's gonna take me on tour and everything.
她很可能会在奥斯汀开演唱会
She'll probably do a concert in Austin.
我可以给你免费门票
I could get you free tickets.
也许吧，也许我能借到我爸的车
Maybe. Guess I could borrow my dad's car.
我会等他喝醉，有时他会醉
I'll wait till he gets drunk. Sometimes he passes out.
我能玩下你的滑板吗？
Do you think I could try your skateboard?
好啊
Okay.
我是柯里郡的主播，约翰 我在那张桌子前坐了15年
I'm the king of Curry County, John, and I've been 15 years at this desk.
我很理解，泰德 不要逼我叫保安
I feel for you, Ted. Don't make me call security.
天哪！
Holy crap!
你，过去！坐好！
You, desk! Sit!
伙计们，30秒后我们就直播！
People, we go live in 30 seconds!
从现在起，开始计时！
From this point on, the news counts!
太兴奋了，我的老家口音都带出来了，老天！
So excited, I got my accent back. My god!
图象准备！
And cue graphics!
音乐准备！
And cue music!
准备！
And cue!
晚上好，我是麦迪逊 从新墨西哥州柯里郡为您现场直播
Good evening. This is Madison, coming to you from Curry County, New Mexico.
在过去的24小时里，美国总统大选…
Over the last 24 hours, the American political process...
到了最关键的时刻 全世界的人们都…
has ground to a virtual standstill as the world watches...
在等待着选举的结果 今天早些时候，我发现了…
waiting for the outcome of an election. Today, I uncovered the identity...
全世界都在寻找的神秘人物
of the person the entire world has been looking for.
这名决定大选结果的关键选民
The one swing voter who will decide the election.
那些急于想知道结果的人 可能会非常失望了
Those of you hoping to hear that decision will be sorely disappointed.
因为你们将要见到一个注册的独立选民…
Because you are about to meet a registered independent...
说他还未做决定
who claims to be keeping an open mind.
想象下，在这个人的肩上…
Imagine, on this man's shoulders...
承载着自由世界的未来
stands the future of the free world.
我就是那种人
Just the kind of guy I am.
让我们再也别说，一张票没有意义了
Let it never again be said, that a single vote counts for nothing.
巴德！
Bud!
干嘛？
What?
外面有人
There's some people outside.
老天，你不要再这样子搞醒我了，好不好？
Geez, you gotta stop waking me up like this, okay?
这样会吓死我的
You're gonna kill me.
外面有人！
There are some people outside!
人？
People?
老天！
God!
不是，不是那边！在前门外面！
No, not there! Out front!
噢，天…干嘛呀这是？
Oh, God... What now?
- 老爸，快点！ - 是的，我在走，宝贝
- Dad, hurry up! - Yeah, I'm going, honey.
外面有很多人
There's a lot of people out there.
好的，宝贝 我们看看外面有什么大不了的
Okay, honey, let's see what the fuss is all about.
那是他吗？
Is that him?
巴德！
Bud!
约翰逊先生，你做决定了吗？
Mr. Johnson, any decisions yet?
- 他妈的！ - 他们要干嘛？
- Holy shit! - What do they want?
我不知道
I don't know.
把电视打开，宝贝
Go turn the TV on, baby.
我们现在正处于历史性时刻
We are in the midst of a historic moment.
这名关键选民已经被确认
The swing voter has finally been identified.
我们现在是在新墨西哥州德士古镇的 一辆拖车边做现场报道
We go live now to a trailer in Texico, New Mexico.
埃里斯特・约翰逊几分钟前现身了
Earnest Johnson made an appearance just moments ago.
很显然，他被现场的媒体吓到了
Apparently, overwhelmed by the media presence.
兰德里先生 您认识埃里斯特・约翰逊先生有多久了？
And Mr. Landry, exactly how long have you known Earnest Johnson?
埃里斯特・约翰逊？ 嗨，埃里斯特！
Earnest Johnson? Hey, Earnest!
- 你是说巴德吗？ - 我们是一起长大的
- You mean Bud? - We all grew up together.
你们怎么看他将肩负…
How do you think he's shouldering the responsibility...
挑选出下一届美国总统的重任？
of picking the next President of the United States?
呃，我肯定…
Well, I'm sure that...
埃里斯特现在吓得都尿裤子了
Earnest is... crapping his pants.
他是个好人，他会好好选的
He's a good guy. He likes to treat them good.
我们曾经把车都给点着了！
We used to light the mesa back here on fire!
都是我的错，是不是？
It's all my fault, isn't it?
不！不是，不是，不是，宝贝，不是你
No! No, no, no, baby, no.
如果我没有让你失望的话这些也不会发生
None of this would have happened if I hadn't let you down.
我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
呃…
Well...
我得回去见见这些人
I'm gonna back these people up.
他妈的！
Holy shit!
太多了！
There's so many!
呃，我走出去，对吧？我…
Ok, I'm just gonna go out there, right? I'm gonna...
我出去告诉那些人不是我投的票
I'm gonna walk out there and tell those people it wasn't me who voted.
不行，你不能说！
No, you can't!
为什么不行？
Why not?
你已经面对法官在圣经前发过誓了 承认是你做的一切
You swore to that judge, on a Bible and everything.
什么？大半夜的，那不算数的！
What? That was the middle of the night. That can't count!
你已经发誓了，巴德 选民欺诈是重罪
You were under oath, Bud. Voter fraud is a felony.
再犯一项罪 他们就会带走我
And one more felony and they take me away from you.
你说的对，他妈的！ 我死定了！
You're right. Shit! I am down to one!
我们怎么办？
What do we do?
我们不得不撒谎了
We lie. We have to.
好吧，好主意 这只是个善意的谎话
Okay, that's a good plan. Just a little white lie is all this is.
- 只有我们知道 - 只有我们俩知道
- Between us. - Just between us.
谁知道呢，也许这事儿，所有这些…
Who knows, maybe this thing, all these...
也许这些人，他们会走的
Maybe all these people, they just go away.
停下！停下！
Stop! Stop!
这是什么鬼地方？
What the hell is this?
这是我们能找到的最大的地方了
The biggest space we could find.
我们怎么做？ 围绕一个人来搞竞选？
How we gonna do this? Build a campaign around one man?
- 我不知道该怎么做 - 交给我吧
- I don't know how to do this. - You're gonna leave it to me.
我们能搞定他的，唐！ 我们会搞定这家伙的
We're gonna win him, Don! We're gonna win this guy.
我们让事情朝我们的方向发展！
We got the issues on our side!
- 说得好！ - 他会喜欢我的！
- There you go! - He's gonna love me!
为什么不呢？
What's not to love?
我们有麻烦了 我要你挖出埃里斯特・约翰逊的所有资料
We're in trouble. I need you to dig up everything you can on Earnest Johnson.
跟他的家人聊，跟他的朋友聊
Talk to his family, his friends.
我要知道他读什么样的书 他看什么样的电视
I want to know what he reads, what television show he watches.
他的爱好，偏好的食物 希望，梦想，所有的
His hobbies, his favorite foods, his hopes, his dreams, everything.
所有需要做的就是赢得一个美国人的心！
All we have to do is win over one American mind!
你看，我只是在想，马蒂
You know, I was just thinking, Marty.
我得认识这个约翰逊老兄，自己去
I'd like to get to know this Bud Johnson. Personally.
好，行
Okay. Good.
或许可以带他出去吃冰淇淋
Maybe take him out for some ice cream.
冰淇淋？
Ice cream?
哪个成年人不喜欢冰淇淋呢？
What grown man doesn't like ice cream?
学历不高，连小学都没上多久
No higher education, not much lower education.
离了婚的单亲爸爸，最近刚被炒
Divorced single father, recently laid off.
我们第一步行动是什么？
What's our first step?
把你们弄到一起 看看你能不能说服他站在我们一边
Put you in a room together. See if you persuade him to come over to our side.
我喜欢，他和我在一起 没错，聊下想法，看看有什么结果
I like it. Him and me in a room. Yes, talking ideas, seeing what comes up.
好计划，我会给你一些话题的
Great plan. I'll get you some talking points.
我擅长即兴发挥
I'm good off the cuff already.
当然拉！ 我们只是把各种各样的想法都集中起来
Of course! We're just gonna get an itty bitty think tank together.
我们去查下资料 看看你们俩有什么共同话题
We'll run the data, see what you two could possibly have in common.
你的请求已经被接受了
Your petition has been processed.
根据新墨西哥州法第11章、第13条、第1款规定
And in accordance with New Mexico state law, Chapter 1, Article 13, Section 11.
你能不能帮我们让那些新闻记者离远一点儿？
Could you do us a favor and back these news people up a little bit?
我们昨晚都睡不成觉了
We could barely sleep last night.
选民埃里斯特・约翰逊，在此被授予…
Said voter Earnest Johnson, is hereby authorized...
从今天起的十天内重新投票的权利
to recast his vote 10 days from today along official.
那里有一个很肥的家伙 他一直靠在我的卡车上…
And there's a fat guy there, he keeps leaning on my truck...
头发都贴在我的后视镜上了
fixing his hair in my side mirror.
选民埃里斯特・约翰逊，在此被授予…
Said voter, Earnest Johnson, is hereby authorized to recast his vote...
从今天起的十天内重新投票的权利 谨此通告
10 days from today. Along official documentary notification...
联邦监管局
to both state, federal regulatory authorities.
巴德，从现在起生活就会有点不同了
Bud, life's gonna be a little different from now on.
你需要全天候的保护
You'll need security around the clock.
为什么？
For what?
你出名了
You're a household name.
这个国家所有吃政治饭的人都会到这儿来
Every political nut job in the country is gonna make their way down here.
十天内，你会做出自由世界里最重要的决定
In 10 days, you gonna make the most important decision in the free world.
我们的职责就是保证结果公平顺利的出现
And it is our job to make sure this thing comes off fair and square.
所以，如果你觉得我们还需要知道什么…
So, if there's anything that you think we need to know...
比如什么？
Like what?
比如过后我们会发现的事情
Something we may find out later.
现在说出来比以后说好
Better now, than later.
没有，先生， 没有什么要说的
No, sir, there's nothing to know.
莫莉！莫莉！莫莉！
Molly! Molly! Molly!
- 简直不敢相信，她是他女儿！ - 谁是他女儿？
- I don't believe it. She's his daughter! - Who's his daughter?
美联储主席，赢得作文比赛的女孩儿
The Chairman of the Fed, the girl that won the essay contest.
记得吗，我报道过她，选举日的时候？
Remember, I ran the story on her, election day?
太棒了！电视台想给她爸做一次采访
This is perfect! The network wants to do an interview with her daddy.
我不会利用这个小女孩儿的！
I'm not going to use this little girl!
我以前告诉过你，我是个正直的人 像泼拉・赞恩一样
I've told you this before. I have integrity, like Paula Zahn.
我见过泼拉・赞恩
I met Paula Zahn.
泼拉・赞恩在我朋友当服务员的地方吃饭，呃？
Paula Zahn eats where my friend is a waiter, alright?
我不想伤害你感情，你成不了泼拉・赞恩
I don't want to hurt your feelings, you're no Paula Zahn.
成不了泼拉・赞恩？
No Paula Zahn?
我定的这个报道，它是我的
I booked this story. It was me.
好 那就是为什么这里的每个人都想踢走你的原因
Yes, that's why everybody here is trying to rip it out from under you.
你想在纽约有一席之地？ 你想在洛杉矶有一席之地？
You want a desk in New York, you want a desk in Los Angeles?
忘掉你在新闻学院学的东西吧
Forget everything you learned in journalism school.
那都不新了，不适应生活了 这个更大，现在是电视时代！
This isn't new anymore. This isn't life. This is bigger. This is television!
约翰逊一家已经被保护起来
The Johnsons have been virtually besieged inside their trailer.
但是我们幸运的采访到给他们送披萨的人
But we're lucky to be joined by their pizza delivery man.
你怎么描述埃里斯特・约翰逊现在的状态？
How would you characterize Earnest Johnson's state of mind?
我能说的就是，他很饿
Mostly I'd say, he was hungry.
他很饿
He was hungry.
那么，您现在看到的是
Well, there you have it.
我再不给他小费了
I ain't tipping him anymore.
我应该去修剪下哈蒂太太的榆树
I ought to trim Mrs. Hardy's elm.
看起来像是快长到我们屋顶上了 你怎么看？
Looks like it's moving in our roof. What do you think?
很难说，你看呢？
Hard to tell. What do you think?
确实是
Definitely.
自从成了世界上被搜索最多的小镇后…
Since has become the most Googled town in the world...
几乎取代了吉哈德
narrowly edging out in Jihad.
老天！
Holy crap!
- 你是巴德？ - 是！
- You Bud? - Yeah!
你是理查德・佩蒂
You're Richard Petty.
说对了，老兄
You got it, man.
等等，宝贝！车王来了！
Hold on. Honey! It's the king!
我有个朋友在公路那边希望你能见见 想去兜个风吗？
I got a friend down the road I want you to meet. You wanna go for a ride?
当然！我的女儿也能去吗？
Yes! Could my daughter come?
那样的话，或许你来开更好 随便你带什么！
In that case, maybe you'd better drive. Precious cargo and all!
等一分钟，佩蒂先生 嘿，胖子！
Just a minute, Mr. Petty. Hey, Chubby!
车没跑起来，别不把它当回事儿！ 快出去！
Just because it ain't rolling, don't make it furniture! Back out of here!
快来，宝贝！我们出发！
Come on, baby! We gotta go!
你是理查德・佩蒂！
You're Richard Petty!
莫莉！照张相，宝贝
Molly! Get a picture, honey.
如果你早两天告诉我我会开你的道奇车…
If you told me two days ago that I'd be driving your Dodge...
- 照了吗？ - 照了
- Did you get it? - Yes.
再照一张，照到我的下巴，像这样
Get one more. Get it with my chin out a little bit. Like that.
像个英雄
Like a hero.
我告诉你，你是个疯子！
I told you, you crazy!
你还没见过疯狂的呢
You ain't seen nothing yet.
巴德
Bud!
这是总统的专机
This is the President's plane.
你好，你一定是莫莉了 我是福克斯先生，我为总统工作
Hello, you be Molly. I'm Mr. Fox, I work with the President.
你好，你好，巴德，马蒂・福克斯
Hi. Hi. Bud, Martin Fox.
- 你好 - 你好吗？请进
- Hello. - How are you? Come in.
请把帽子脱掉，你的帽子
Take your hat off please. Your hat.
那么，这就是约翰逊一家了
So, this is the Johnson family.
欢迎来到空军一号 你好，莫莉
Welcome to Air Force One. Hi, Molly.
- 谢谢邀请，先生 - 这是我的荣幸
- Thanks for having us, sir. - It's a pleasure.
- 总统先生 - 呃？
- Mr. President. - Huh?
叫他总统先生
Call him Mr. President.
真是荣幸，总统先生
It's an honor, Mr. President.
很荣幸见到你，巴德 我能叫你巴德吗？
It's an honor to meet you, Bud. May I call you Bud?
行，总统先生
Yes, Mr. President.
进来，快进来
Come on in, come on.
天，这个…
God, this...
这里真棒！
This place is it's really something!
这是我在天上的小家
It's my little home in the sky.
有点像，像是长了翅膀的拖车
It's kinda, like a trailer with wings.
很不错的比喻，巴德
Fine analogy, Bud.
莫莉，前几天我看了你在电视上的演讲
Molly, I saw your speech on TV the other night.
非常吸引人！
Very impressive!
- 说谢谢，宝贝 - 谢谢，总统先生
- Say thank you, baby. - Thank you, Mr. President.
- 你一定是个很骄傲的父亲 - 是的，先生
- You must be a very proud father. - Yes, sir.
天，抱歉，总统先生
God, I'm sorry. Mr. President.
你能看出她是我们家的小大人
You can see why she's definitely the brains of our operation.
我懂你的意思，我们都需要一个＂莫莉＂
I know what you mean. We all need a Molly.
马蒂，就是我的＂莫莉＂
Marty here, is my Molly.
很对，莫莉 我打赌像你一样聪明的小孩儿…
That's right. Molly, I bet a smart kid like you...
一定想要看看作战指挥室
would love to see the war room.
不，谢谢
No, thanks.
为什么我们不去看一下呢 你爸爸和总统要聊一会儿天
Why don't we have a peek and then your dad and the President can have a talk.
去吧，宝贝，爸爸要和总统聊天
Go on, Honey. Daddy has to talk to the President.
她可很有个性呀！
She's a firecracker!
是的，先生，她是我的全部！
Yes, sir, she's the whole deal!
不介意我去看下作战指挥室吧，总统先生
I wouldn't mind seeing the war room, Mr. President.
我等会儿给你看，还有 请叫我安迪
I'll show it to you later. And please, call me Andy.
- 安迪？ - 是啊
- Andy? - Yeah.
你肯定吗，因为那个人…
Are you sure, that-that other guy...
我知道，这里有点太严肃了
I know, things can get a little formal around here.
总司令，管理整个国家什么的，请坐
Commander in Chief, running the country and all that. Please.
我只是一个普通人，跟你一样…
I am just an ordinary man, like you...
可以坐下来跟你喝杯啤酒的那种人
The kinda guy you can sit down and have a beer with.
你想喝啤酒吗，巴德？
Would you like a beer, Bud?
啤酒？
A beer?
不开玩笑？
No shit?
不开玩笑
No shit.
那么，呃…
Well, then...
- 好，好啊，好，安迪 - 好的！
- Yes. Hell, yeah, Andy. - Okay!
戴维，你能给我们拿两杯啤酒来吗？
David, would you get us a couple of beers, please?
- 非常感谢 - 那么…
- Thank you very much. - So...
你可以去跟你的朋友说了
you're gonna have some story to tell your friends.
我在报纸上读过关于你的事儿 他们说你从来没输过一场竞选
I read about you in the paper. They say you've never lost an election.
很对，从报纸上你可以读到很多
That's right. You can learn a lot from reading the newspaper.
他们也说你从来不相信任何事
They also said that you don't believe in anything anymore.
即使是出卖母亲的灵魂
Even if it meant selling your mother's soul.
不是，你看，不是，那是恶意中伤 因为我母亲是个很伟大的…
No, see, no, see that's libelous, Because my mother is a wonderful...
伟大的，伟大的女人
wonderful, wonderful woman.
如果你见过我母亲，你就会明白
If you met my mother, you'd understand.
你是个球迷吗，巴德？
You a football fan, Bud?
呃，我是个美国人，对吧？
Well, I'm an American, aren't I?
在高中我偶尔会去玩
I played a little in high school.
现在呢？打哪个位置？
Did you now? What position?
我当四分卫
I was quarterback.
我一直认为橄榄球是个战略游戏 跟外交很像
I always thought football was a strategic game. A lot like diplomacy.
你进攻，防卫 总统就像是你的四分卫…
You got your offense, your defense, the President is like your quarterback...
美国选民…
and the American voters...
呃…他们就像教练
Well... they're like the coach.
我没来没这样想过
Never thought of it that way.
现在教练的职责就是确保…
Now the coach's job is to make sure...
在球赛的关键时刻有合适的人控球
that the right man has the football at the critical time.
我完全明白你说的，安迪
I know exactly what you mean, Andy.
是吗？
Do you?
也许还没有
Maybe not.
请拿个球过来
Bring in the football, please.
巴德
Bud.
你想控球吗？
You wanna hold the football?
那里面装的是球？
There's a football in there?
那个箱子里装的是启动密码…
That case holds the launch codes...
用来启动美国核武器
to America's nuclear arsenal.
那就是选举的目的
That's what this election's all about.
启动密码就像…导弹之类的玩意儿？
Launch codes like... missiles and shit?
我希望你把美国想象成一只队伍…
I want you to pretend that America is a team...
- 你是教练 - 好吧
- and you're the coach. - Okay.
假设现在是踢第四节比赛 我们正在控球，但是落后五分
Let's say it's the 4th quarter. We've got possession, but we're down by five.
朝鲜已经进入我们的十五码线内…
North Korea has us pinned in our own fifteenth line...
危急时刻，你会怎么做？
with one second on the dooms day clock. What are you doing to do?
没错，你要做决定 胜利和失败之间唯一的区别就是…
Okay, you go long. The only thing standing between victory and defeat...
一次成功的投射，一次命中
is a successful Hail Mary. One play.
你会把球传给谁，巴德？
Who are you gonna give the ball to, Bud?
你会把你的希望寄托在一些散漫的后补…
Do you pin your hopes on some liberal second string quarterback...
上场都不超过五分钟的人身上吗？ 当然你不会
who hasn't had five minutes in the big show? Of course you don't.
你会作出明智的选择
You do the smart thing.
唯一的事情就是 你需要派出最好的队员，这个队员…
The only thing. You go with your strongest arm, the man...
能带你打赢整个赛季 他从来不会让你失望
who's carried you through the season, who's never let you down.
巴德，美国人民的希望寄托在你身上
Bud, America's counting on you.
是的，先生，我不会让他们失望的
Yes, sir. I'm not gonna let them down.
但是，这个
But, here.
我不想弄这个
Wouldn't want to drop the old football.
去炸法国或是其他什么地方的
Blow up France or something.
你打不开的
You couldn't.
需要一堆的密码和特殊的小钥匙
There's a whole bunch of secret codes and these special little keys.
干杯！
Here's to you!
看看这些… 看看他们给我的这些东西，莫莉
Look at all... Look at all this stuff they give us, Molly.
他们给了我总统用的洗发水
They give us the same shampoo that the President uses.
很好
Great.
那么，你们俩聊了什么？
So, what did you guys talk about?
- 事情 - 什么事情？
- Stuff. - What stuff?
呃…
You know...
大人的事
grown up stuff.
比如？
Like?
比如…
Like...
巴德！
Bud!
什么事情？
What stuff?
比如大人的事 你知道的，训练，橄榄球
Like grown up stuff. You know, coaching. Football.
地热核战争
Geothermal nuclear war.
安迪是，很棒…很棒的一个人
Andy's, a great... great guy.
他不是安迪，他是美国总统
He's not Andy. He's the President of the United States.
他只是想要你的选票
And he just wants your vote.
哈，猜猜看？他会得到的
And gee, guess what? He's gonna get it.
你不能这么快做决定！
It's not even yours to give!
你会…
You're gonna...
把一切都搞砸的
ruin everything.
而且，总统邀请我去看球…
Andy, the President, invited me to watch the game...
- 周一晚上和他一起 - 那是行贿！
- with him on Monday night. - That's a bribe!
那不是行贿
That's not a bribe.
- 就是 - 不是的
- Is too. - It is not.
- 就是！ - 就不是！你什么意思，＂就是＂？
- Is too! - Is not! What it is, "too"?
- 你知道些什么呀？ - 比你多
- What the hell do you know? - More than you.
- 你不知道 - 我知道
- You do not. - Do too.
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Fine. - Fine.
你闻到飞机上的皮革味没有？
Did you smell all the leather on that plane?
如果我曾让你感到片刻的欢乐
If I made you feel second best
我很抱歉我没觉察
I'm sorry I was blind
不，宝贝，就那个，就那个，那是威利
No, baby, leave it, leave it. That's Willie.
你一直在我心里
You were always on my mind
嗨，我是威利・纳尔森
Hi, I'm Willie Nelson.
当我不表演的时候，我经常玩这个
And when I'm not performing, I'm usually getting involved.
嘿，巴德，如果你在那里看电视的话…
Hey, Bud, if you're out there and you're watching...
他在跟我讲话！
He's talking to us!
有一个特别的聚会 是为你特别准备的…
There's a special dinner, especially for you in your honor...
是我的好朋友举办的 总统候选人唐纳德・格林利夫
hosted by my good friend and Presidential candidate Donald Greenleaf.
- 今晚见 - 我会去的，威利！
- I'll see you here tonight. - I'll do it, Willie!
越来越奇怪了
This is really getting weird.
民主党还是共和党？
Democrat or a Republican?
我是阿蒂・克拉姆 唐纳德・格林利夫的竞选主管
I'm Art Crumb, Donald Greenleaf's campaign manager.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Nice to meet you. - Same here.
你一定是莫莉了，你的文章真棒 你以后一定会成为政坛新星的
You must be Molly. Quite an essay. You have a future in politics one day.
你也是，总有一天
You might too. One day.
请进吧？
Shall we go in?
亲切一点好吧， 来吧
Not too hard to be nice, come on.
聚会，聚会！
Party. Party!
这边走，请随便
Right this way... make yourselves at home.
你好
Hello.
你看，我们精心准备了自助餐
As you can see, we've got a lovely buffet.
想来杯百威吗，巴德？
Would you like a bud, Bud?
当然
Sure.
看这个，你准备了烤面包加碎肉
Look at that. You got chipped meat on toast.
我妈以前就做这个给我吃
My momma used to make that for me.
- 不是吧？ - 是啊
- No kidding? - Yes.
在这儿你可以随便吃
There's all you can eat.
都是为你举办的
It's all in your honor.
这里有威利・纳尔森的歌 你都可以听
And there's all the Willie Nelson you can listen to.
我知道你是他的粉丝
I understand you're an aficionado.
是的，先生 我曾在＂向威利致敬＂乐队待过五年
Yes, sir, I was in an all Willie tribute band for about five years.
我们自称纳尔森第二
Called ourselves The Half Nelsons.
只唱他的歌？
Only his songs?
也没特别的要求 你看，我有些事要忙
No other request. But you know, I got my own stuff.
那么，你们今晚为何不唱首歌呢？
So, why don't you guys do one of your songs tonight?
但是我的贝司手还在蹲监狱
I would but my rhythm section's incarcerated.
我们找了一些关系
We've pulled a few strings.
- 嘿，巴德！巴德！ - 嘿，伙计们！
- Hey, Bud! Bud! - Hey, boys!
上来！
Come on up!
他们付钱给我们吗？
They paying us?
你真把他们弄出来了啊 谢谢你，找了关系
You really did, you got them out. Thank you. Pull strings.
巴德！老兄！老兄！老兄，看看我！
Bud! Buddy, Buddy! Buddy, look at me!
呃，汉克，真帅 像是参加舞会
Damn, Hank, you look good. Just like prom.
谢谢，谢谢，朋友 这是我一生中最棒的一天
Thank you. Thank you, amigo. This is the best day of my life.
我希望你能见见一个很特别的人
There's someone very special I'd like you to meet.
约翰逊先生！
Mr. Johnson!
唐纳德・格林利夫
Donald Greenleaf.
好紧
Too tight.
聚会真不错，格林利夫先生
Hell of a party you got here, Mr. Greenleaf.
是的，先生 我们民主党人就是一家人
Yes, sir. We democrats are one hell of a party.
叫我唐
Call me Don.
好的，唐
Okay, Don.
舞台等着你呢
The stage awaits.
呃，既然他都这么说了，对吧？
Well, he said so, right?
庞蒂克，庞蒂克（车名）
Pontiac, Pontiac
停在我的后院里
Out there in my backyard.
我要修好它，刷成红色，发动引擎
I'm gonna fix it up, paint it red gonna make that engine go
雪佛兰，雪佛兰
Chevrolet, Chevrolet
时光飞逝，一切一切
Chevy year that running Past fly, this and that
发动引擎，准备好了吗？
Gonna make that engine go You ready?
它们都在我的后院里，那些老爷车
They're all in my backyard Them old cars
我爱它们每一辆
I love everyone of them
莫莉？还记得我吗？
Molly? You remember me?
你好，麦迪逊小姐
Hi, Ms. Madison.
别担心，我没带摄像机
Don't worry, I didn't bring a camera.
我这就开走一辆
I'm gonna get one running yet.
这太疯狂了，我不知道你该怎么办
All this craziness. I don't know how you're doing it.
如果你想谈谈的话 任何时候都可以打给我，好吗？
If you ever want to talk, you call me anytime, okay?
我把名片给你，拿着
I'm gonna give you my card. There you go.
你想采访巴德，是吧？
You want an interview with Bud, right?
我希望他考虑下
I'd like him to think about it.
好吧
Okay.
我这就开走一辆
I'll get one running yet
巴德！你真厉害！
Bud! You're the man!
嗨…我喜欢你，巴德
Well... I like you, Bud.
你真是个天才
You seem to be a real genuine sort of guy.
谢谢，唐
Thanks, Don.
给我说说你自己，你有什么爱好？
Tell me about yourself. You got any hobbies?
只有…
Just...
只有钓鱼
just fishing.
你是个钓鱼佬啊！
You're a fellow angler!
你用什么鱼竿？
What kind of rod do you use?
呃，我用6・5英尺石墨竿 有约翰尼・莫瑞斯签名的系列
Well, I use a six and a half foot graphite Johnny Morris signature series.
很重吧？
Heavy?
一般
Medium heavy.
鱼饵线轴，12磅重
Bait catching reel, twelve pound test.
等一下
Don't tell me.
7英寸的蛆虫，紫色的蠕虫
Seven inch power grub, purple shaky worm.
是啊，先生！ 天，他，他，你很懂行！
Yes, sir! Damn, he, he, you know your equipment!
我还以为你是个贝司手呢
I figured you for a bass man.
呃，我…
Well, I...
只要有可能就带莫莉去
try to take Molly out as much as I can.
前几天我们才在佩科斯河钓了一条鱼 够吃两顿了
We caught a two dinner stripe on the Pecos just the other day.
我很抱歉，巴德
I'm sorry to hear that, Bud.
为什么？
Why?
有项法案决定要把佩科斯河…
There's a bill in the House targeting the Pecos River for...
重新分配
reallocation.
我没听懂
You lost me there.
一个大公司要在那儿建造一座水坝
That's where a big corporation builds a dam.
限制水流 鱼就不能游到他们的产卵地…
Limits the flow of water, the fish can't get to their spawning grounds...
最后所有鱼就死光了
eventually the whole population dies off.
那太糟了 因为我在那儿钓了一辈子的鱼了
That sucks, because I've been fishing there my whole life.
你最好再找一条河了 因为布恩总统已经接受了…
You'd better look for another river, because President Boone has received...
来自能源公司的一千万竞选款…
ten million dollars in contributions from the energy company...
他总会报答他们的
and he's got to pay them back somehow.
呃，嗨，嗨，安迪不会那么做的
Come on, now. Come on, Andy wouldn't do that.
他已经做了，巴德，他已经做了
He already did, Bud. He already did.
那么，你能做些什么吗？
Okay. Can't you do something?
如果我被选为总统
If I'm elected President.
什么？
What?
不，准确告诉我他们说了什么
No, tell me exactly what was said.
保护这个国家的野生环境是我的责任…
It's my commitment to protect the wild places in this country...
为了子孙后代
for future generations.
我也不会只在这里做，巴德
And I'm not going to stop there, Bud.
在你的帮助下，我的政府…
With your help, my administration...
将成为环境保护方面的领导者
will be a leader in environmental protections.
美国同胞们…
My fellow Americans...
我宣布 佩科斯河为国家野生动物保护区！
I give you, the Pecos River National Wildlife Preserve!
这只能被形容为完全的政治逆转…
And what can only be characterized as a complete policy reversal...
总统已经完全疏远了他的大赞助商…
the President has surely alienated his corporate donors...
站在了保护环境一边
by adopting a pro-environment stance.
巴德和莫莉・约翰逊今天也到场…
Bud and Molly Johnson were on hand today...
我们才是主张 保护环境的党啊！
We are the environmental party!
那些混蛋偷走了我们的政治纲领
Those bastards stole our platform.
公共关系部人员 全体待命
Put the PR people on standby.
- 要把施皮格尔曼・菲舍找来吗？ - 太难请了
- You want Spiegelman Fischer? - Too high brow.
- 那些戴ipod的家伙怎么样？ - 不行，拉里，城市味太浓了
- What about those iPod guys? - No, Larry, too urban.
找那些卖米勒淡啤的人
Get the guys who do those Miller Lite spots.
和女孩儿在喷泉里摔跤的那些
The ones with those girls wrestling in the fountain.
我不认识，克拉姆先生
I don't know, Mr. Crumb.
我喜欢那个叫卖的声音 很有节奏感
I like the narrator's voice. His cadence.
给他们打电话
Just call them.
葛洛琳讨厌那些广告，阿蒂 她说它们传达错误的信息
Galena hates those ads, Artie, she says they send the wrong message.
您的妻子不是我们的目标 那个婊子养的才是
Your wife's not our target demographic, that son of a bitch is.
很好
Great.
他用特工把他圈起来了！
He's got the Secret Service running flight patterns!
我们所要做的都要跟这个家伙有关
All we need is an issue that matters to this guy.
一个目标，一个人…
One issue, one man...
一张选票
one vote.
老天
Boy.
这个归我了
I already own it.
好，我要买个旅馆
Alright, I'm gonna buy a hotel.
嗨，我来送巴德・约翰逊的邮包
Hi, there. I've got a delivery for Bud Johnson.
谁寄的？
From who?
大家
From everyone.
告诉我，巴德・约翰逊现在开什么车？
Tell me, what drives Bud Johnson?
现在嘛 一辆89年的雪佛兰・希尔维多拉
Right now, an '89 Chevy Silverado.
你不需要把那个拿起来 不动它，效果更好
You don't have to lift that up. If you leave it, it's probably better.
- 你错过了机会 - 我已经尽力了
- This thing is getting away from you. - I'm doing the best I can.
那就再努力点！ 我还以为你想离开这鬼地方呢！
Do better! I thought you wanted to get out of this shithole town!
我想弄清事实！
I want to get out the facts!
你听见没？咔嗒
You hear that? The clicking.
咔嗒，咔嗒
Click, click.
无数的遥控换台的声音
The sound of a million remote controls changing the channel on your ass.
咔嗒就是完蛋！
Click equals death!
你得给观众看你的理由 这是黄金时段的新闻
You got to get people a reason to watch. This is the prime time news.
关键词，要新奇！
The key word, being new!
给我去找 你被玛丽・哈特搞下去了！
Find me something. You just got taken down by Mary Hart!
巴德，看这里，有什么特别的事情…
Bud, in looking at it, is there any issue in particular that...
触动过你？
has touched you personally?
呃，嗯，内雇
Yeah, yeah, insourcing.
你是说，外包
You mean, outsourcing.
不是，是内雇
No, I mean in.
- 能详细说下吗？ - 呃，嗯…
- Can you elaborate? - Yeah, well...
我以前工作的地方，我认识一群人 他们被解雇了
where I used to work, there's a bunch of guys I know, they got laid off.
不是把我们的活儿 把我们的活儿弄去墨西哥…
Instead of sending our jobs, losing our jobs to Mexico...
他们弄来墨西哥人抢我们的活儿
they're bringing in Mexicans to take our jobs.
然后我们就被解雇了
And we're out.
等等，我能再说一遍吗？ 我想我说的不对
Wait a minute, could I say that again? I don't think that came out right.
说的很好
That came out great.
说的非常好，约翰逊先生
That came out very well, Mr. Johnson.
很真实，中心报道？
Very authentic. Central casting?
边境巡逻？
Border patrol?
那么，他们都是非法劳工？
So, they're actual undocumented workers?
我们更愿意称为非法演员
We prefer undocumented actors.
好的，排练开始了，各就各位！
Alright, rehearsal's up, back it into one please!
但我们是支持移民发展的
But we courted the Pro-lmmigrant movement.
包容性是我们党的基础！ 是我们的根本！
Inclusiveness is the foundation of our party. It's our base!
我们再没有根本了 约翰逊就是我们的根本
We no longer have a base. Bud Johnson's our base.
我都不认识我自己了
I don't even recognize myself anymore.
那个…五彩之家怎么办？
And what about... Rainbow House?
让那个五彩之家见鬼去吧！ 这个家伙讨厌移民
Screw! This guy cares about immigration.
想赢吗？ 先树一尊新的自由神像吧
You wanna win? Go out there and rip the Statue of Liberty a new one!
开始！
And action!
巴德，在过去的四年里，布恩总统…
Bud, in the last four years, President Boone...
放任了上百万的非法移民穿越我们的国境…
has allowed millions of illegal aliens to cross the border...
涌入像洛杉矶，纽约，德士古这样的城市
Flooding cities like Los Angeles, New York and Texico.
在你的帮助下，巴德 我的政府会加强国境的管理…
With your help, Bud, my administration will mend our broken borders...
并停止向内引进劳动力
and stop insourcing.
投给格林利夫就是投给美国…
A vote for Greenleaf is a vote for America...
以美国人为重的美国
An America where Americans come first.
这是我们的国家，巴德 帮助我实现吧
This land is our land, Bud. Help me keep it that way.
亲爱的汤米 看了你六年级的来信后我非常感动
Dear Tommy, I was very moved by the letter from your 6th grade class.
全球变暖是个很严重的问题…
Global warming is a serious issue...
我保证我会和候选人首先讨论这个问题
and I promise to make it a top priority in my discussions with the candidates.
＂亲爱的安德生太太，谢谢你的来信
"Dear Mrs. Anderson, thank you for your letter.
我会尽一切努力来促使候选人关注健康保险的＂
I am doing everything I can to press the candidates about health insurance."
＂亲爱的奥森先生 你对工作保障的担心我深有同感
"Dear Mr. Olsen, I sympathize with your fears about job security.
我向你保证，我不会忽视这个问题的…
I promise you, I will not ignore the issues...
对于教育，退伍军人，经济…
Education, veterans, the economy...
公共医疗，环境保护
health care, the environment.
我一直都在不懈争取，尽一切努力
I am working tirelessly. I'm doing everything I can.
真诚的，埃里斯特・巴德・约翰逊＂
Sincerely, Earnest Bud Johnson."
放！
Now!
噢，我的天！唐！
Oh, my God! Don!
那个笨蛋摔倒了！
The goose is down!
这是几根手指？
How many fingers?
美国想知道巴德・约翰逊是个什么样的人
America wants to know what it's like to be Bud Johnson.
还不错
It doesn't suck.
快走！
Come on!
我听说你接到了求婚信，是真的吗？
I've heard you've received marriage proposals in the mail, true?
呃，你可以告诉九月小姐…
Yeah, you can tell that Miss September...
我会考虑的
that I'm weighing my options.
快点，巴德！
Hurry up, Bud!
人物杂志评选您为年度最性感男士
People Magazine named you the Sexiest Man of the Year.
是吗？呃，我应该说什么？
Yeah? Well, what can I say?
不敢当！
Guilty as charged!
这些人！
These people!
莫莉，你怎么看你的爸爸？你怎么看？
Molly, what do you think of your Dad? What do you think?
来啊，来 拿摄像机的，把头抬起来，混蛋！
Go ahead, go on. Stick your head up with that little camera. You turd!
巴德…巴德！
Bud... Bud!
- 不许动！ - 够了
- Freeze! - Stop.
够了
Stop.
够了！
Stop!
嗨，莫莉？这只是个巧克力 那个打枪的给的
Come on, Molly? It's just chocolate. From the gun people.
- 我给你做了熏肉和鸡蛋 - 你做的？
- I fixed you bacon and eggs. - You did?
太好了！
That's nice!
- 我希望你看起来好点 - 什么事？
- I want you to look nice. - What's the occasion?
我想你应该跟一个人聊聊
There's someone I think you should talk to.
坐下
Sit.
她跟其他人都不同，我想她心肠不坏
She's different than all the others. I think her heart's in the right place.
我希望你不要说些难堪的话，好不好？
I want you to try not to say anything embarrassing, okay?
- 跟谁？ - 麦迪逊小姐
- To who? - Ms. Madison.
- 那个电视主持？ - 她在外面
- The TV woman? - She's outside.
- 她在外面？ - 是的，在厨房
- She's outside? - Yes. In the kitchen.
- 她在我们家厨房？ - 是的
- She's in our kitchen? - Yes.
表现正常点
Just try and be normal.
我很臭吗？
Do I smell?
呃，把香水给我 老天！我才玩了一会儿！
Then, give me the Old Spice. God darn it! I was just having some fun!
莫莉，这些鸡蛋太好吃了
Molly, these eggs are amazing.
是啊，当然了
Yes, they sure are.
谢谢
Thanks.
呃…
Well...
我喜欢你的新发型
I like this new look on you.
很好，不是吗？很职业化
It's good, isn't it? Professional.
是啊，很好
Yeah, its damn good.
呃，巴德，我以前想能采访你
Anyway, Bud, I was thinking about interviewing you over the next days.
认识下你还有你的想法
Get to know you and your thoughts.
你认为人们真的在乎我想什么吗？
Think people really care about my thoughts?
我很关心你会做出的选择
I really do considering the choice you're about to make.
你说你去过德士古？
Did you say you went to Texico High?
她去过，她姓莫拉莱斯
She did. Only her name was Morales.
莫拉莱斯？
Morales?
开玩笑吧 你是鲍比・莫拉莱斯的一个妹妹？
You're kidding. One of Bobby Morales little sisters?
是啊，我就是
Yeah, that's me.
世界太小了！
Small world!
镇子很小 那么，巴德，你准备好了吗？
Small town. Then, Bud, are you ready?
现在可以吗？
It's a good time?
呃，行啊，拍吧
Yeah, go ahead, shoot.
谢谢，巴德
Thanks, Bud.
咱们从同性恋结婚开始谈起吧
Why don't we get started with your opinion of gay marriage.
天！非谈这个吗？
Shit! Do we have to?
- 那么，你是反对了 -  我…没有，我没有那么说
- So, you're against it. - I... no, I didn't say that.
那么，你是什么态度？
Then, what is your position?
我没意见，事实上，这对我不重要
I don't have a position on it. Actually, I don't give a rat's ass about it.
我爸总是说国王在他的领地可以为所欲为
My daddy always said whatever a king does in his castle is his business.
所以我猜有两个皇后也没问题
I guess the same can go for two queens.
我是布恩总统 很高兴向你介绍我的一些朋友
I'm President Boone, and I'd like you to meet a few friends of mine.
他们是医生，治安官员
They're our doctors, and our peace officers.
他们教育我们的孩子 衷心地在军队服役
They teach our children, they serve nobly in our armed forces.
长久以来，同性恋的美国人…
For two long, homosexual Americans...
一直在被他们热爱的国家所迫害
have been persecuted by the country they love.
作为总统，如果我再次连任的话 将会首先敞开大门
This President, if re-elected, will implement the open door initiative.
让同性恋的美国人，男性或女性 都能自豪地走出枷锁
Gay Americans alike will be able to proudly step out of the closet...
同样走向圣坛，交换彼此的誓言
and on to the alter, to exchange the sacred vows enjoyed by the rest of us.
巴德，有了你的帮助 共和党的政府…
Bud, With your help, this Republican administration...
将会赞成同性婚姻
will say, I do. To gay marriage.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意！
I do!
我愿意
I do.
我愿意！
I do!
- 我成功了！ - 就是那样，宝贝！
- I did it! - That 'a way, baby!
当我们还是小孩儿的时候 这是周末唯一能玩的
When we were kids, this was the only thing to do on the weekends.
现在也是
Still is.
好球，巴德
Well done, Bud.
看到了？
See?
让我们谈一些现实的话题
Let's get to some real issues.
好啊
Okay.
反对堕胎还是支持流产的合法化？ 你站在哪一边？
Pro-life or pro-choice? Where do you stand?
呃…
Well...
生命很美好，现在也是
Life's pretty good. Right about now.
所以，你反对堕胎了？
So, you're pro-life then?
谁不是呢？
Who isn't?
阿蒂
Artie.
- 阿蒂 - 干嘛？
- Artie. - What?
我感觉不对，我们走错方向了
I don't feel comfortable with this. We're headed in the wrong direction.
不是，这很好
No, it's gonna be great.
- 阿蒂 - 开始！开始！
- Artie. - And action! Action!
开始，唐纳德！
And action, Donald!
我们的未来是什么？
What is our future?
我会告诉你我们的未来是什么
I'll tell you what our future is.
这些孩子，跟你的女儿一样，巴德
Children like these, like your daughter, Bud.
快乐，自由，充满希望
Happy, free, full of promise.
但是想象一个没有了这些欢声笑语的世界
But imagine a world without all this joyous laughter.
我指的是堕胎
I'm talking about abortion.
布恩总统，他说他反对堕胎
President Boone, he claims he's pro-life.
但是在他的领导下…
But yet under his leadership...
还没能做出任何实质上的贡献 来改变罗诉韦德法案
no significant challenge has been leveled against Roe versus Wade.
有了你的帮助，巴德 格林利夫的政府…
With your help, Bud, the Greenleaf administration...
将会尽一切努力改变这种非人道的法案
will lead a genuine effort to reverse this inhumane court decision.
所以，加入我和民主党吧 我们会保护所有生命…
So, join me and the Democrats as we preserve all life...
这是在延续上帝的杰作
That's for filling God's intelligent design.
我是唐纳德・格林利夫 我坚持这个立场
I'm Donald Greenleaf and I approve this message.
看起来不对啊
That don't seem right.
他这样说是因为你说你不喜欢堕胎
He's only saying that because you said you didn't like abortion.
呃，但是我并没有那么说
Yeah, but I didn't say that.
你告诉她你选择生命优先权
You told that you were pro-life.
那又怎么样？
So what?
选择生命优先就是反对堕胎 罗诉韦德法案？嘿！
Pro-life means anti-abortion. Roe versus Wade? Hello!
真搞不懂你
This isn't working.
我还以为有帮助呢，结果更糟
I thought would help, but it's just worse.
是你要我跟她聊的
You're the one that wanted me to talk to her.
我以为你会喜欢她，她聪明，而且人很好…
I thought you might like her. She's smart, and nice...
不像以前跟你鬼混的那些女人
not like the other women you spend time with.
哪些女人，莫莉？
Which women would those be, Molly?
跳舞的那个，巴德
The ones that dance, Bud.
呃，至少她们都有工作
Well, at least they got jobs.
一切都乱了
It's all getting turned upside down now.
什么乱了？
What's all getting turned upside down?
你在毁灭美国！
You're ruining America!
- 我什么？ - 你在毁灭美国！
- I'm what? - You're ruining EUA!
- 我在毁灭美国？ - 是的！
- I'm ruining EUA? - Yes!
什么？
What?
我只是走了点运…
What I finally am is having a little good luck...
是你给我的！
and you're giving me shit about it!
你知道这些对我这样的人意味着什么吗？
You know what all this means for someone like me?
我也有过梦想，或许不是这个…
I had dreams once. Maybe it weren't this...
那是在五年级，我也有梦想
but I was in the fifth grade, so I had them.
现在呢…
And now...
我都已经是个无名之辈了，可是…
I pretty much been headed on a road for being a nobody and now that...
我成名了 你却不能忍受我得到的一点关注
I am a somebody, you can't stand that I'm getting a little attention.
- 一点？ - 是的，一点
- A little? - Yeah, a little.
或许我应该说出事实，巴德
Maybe I'll tell the truth, Bud.
- 事实？ - 是的
- The truth? - Yes.
什么事实？
The truth about what?
也许我应该告诉每个人 是我在你喝醉的时候投的票！
Maybe I'll tell everybody it was me who tried to vote while you got drunk!
我不在乎他们会不会把我带走
I don't care if they take me away from you.
莫莉…嘿，莫莉！
Molly... Hey, Molly!
让我自己待着
Leave me alone.
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Fine. - Fine.
好吧
Fine.
能签个名吗？
Could you sign it?
没问题，柯里
Sure thing, Curly.
嗨，巴德…你替我们亲了总统的屁股吗？
Hey, Bud... did you give the President's butt a kiss from us?
你想说什么，沃特？
You got something to say, Walt?
不光是我，巴德 没有人喜欢你对镇子所做的事
It's not just me, Bud. No one likes what you done to this town.
你投票后都发生了什么呀？
What's gonna happen after you vote?
每个人都会卷铺盖走人 跟来之前一样
Everyone's gonna pack up and leave us in the same shape as they found us.
巴德，你上电视了！
Bud, you're on TVagain!
嗨，巴德，你又上电视了
Hey, Bud, you're on TV again.
人们不应该再说 巴德・约翰逊是民主的象征了
People have to stop saying Bud Johnson is good for democracy.
他让我们成了全世界的笑柄
He's made us the laughing stock of the entire world.
媒体像狗仔队一样跟在他屁股后面 因为…
The news media follows him around like a bunch of paparazzi, because...
我们更关注他是个新闻人物…
we're more concerned with his fifteen minutes of fame...
而不是他将做出的决定
than we are with the choice he's about to make.
真的有人在乎这个人吗？
Is anybody really listening to this guy?
清醒点吧，美国！ 巴德・约翰逊就是个笨蛋！
Wake up, America! Bud Johnson, is a dumbass!
您的妻子来了，格林利夫先生
Your wife has just arrived, Mr. Greenleaf.
感谢老天！太好了
Thank God! Good.
请不要惹他不高兴
Please, don't upset him.
你什么时候来的？我太想你了！
When did you get in? I missed you so much!
你就让这么一个二百五毁了你自己
You are letting this two bit hack destroy you.
你现在就是共和党指责的样子
You are everything that the Republicans accused you of being.
懦弱的外行人，毫无立场
A spineless amateur. Afraid to take a position.
我不是害怕坚持立场
I am not afraid to take a position.
好吧，有时我有别的想法
Okay, sometimes I have second thoughts.
但是哪一个有思想的人不是如此呢？
But what thinking person doesn't?
你以前是代表民主党的，你们俩
You used to stand for something. Both of you.
让她走吧
Let her go.
你怎么了，阿蒂？
What's happened to you, Art?
这次我会赢
I'm gonna win this time.
你以前也进行过有意义的宣传
You used to run campaigns that meant something.
如果我支持的候选人会赢的话 那就是有意义！
They would have meant something if the candidates I backed had won!
你知道拥有了所有理论是怎样吗？
You know what's like to be on the right side of every issue on the theory stage?
每次都是失望？
The hope that rocks with every loss?
这次不会，再也不会了
Not this time. Never again.
回去工作！每个人！
Back to work! Everybody!
看看！
Look at that!
你烤的热狗，刚刚好
You burnt the hot dog, just a little bit.
我就喜欢这样的！
Just the way I like them!
- 巴德？ - 呃？
- Bud? - Yes?
我想我们应该要求开一个总统辩论会
I think we should ask for a Presidential debate.
嗨！我们就不能谈点别的吗？
Come on! Can't we just talk about something else for one night?
就一分钟？也许？
Just for a minute? Maybe?
你刚跟我说的什么？
What did you just say to me?
总统辩论会，你可以提问
A Presidential debate. Where you get to ask questions.
嗨，算了吧
Please. Just stop.
这很重要！这能帮你做决定
It's important! It could help you decide.
帮我做决定
Help me decide.
想想你都跟我说了什么
Think about what you're saying to me.
我有！你应该读读给你的来信
I have! You should read all this mail you've been getting.
人们写信给你寻求帮助
People are writing to you for help.
人们写信给我，那又怎样？
People are writing me letters. So what?
我帮不了他们
I can't help these people.
你可以为他们说话
You can speak for them.
你能为我那么做吗？
Will you do it for me?
我做这些都是为了你！
I'm doing this all because of you!
我们刚刚确认 这周三晚有场总统辩论会…
Confirmed, one Presidential debate will occur this Wednesday night...
约翰逊先生会向每位候选人提问
at which Mr. Johnson will ask both candidates a set of questions.
第二天，他会再次投票
The following day, he'll cast his vote.
巴德，你会在辩论会上问什么？
Bud, what will you ask at the debate?
事实是，我还不知道，但是我…
Truth is, I don't know yet, but I'm...
我会知道的
I'll figure it out.
我讨厌辩论，他们会耍诈
I hate debates. Where they try-to trick you.
我知道，但是你会没事的
I know, but you'll be fine.
我们有两天时间来把这事搞定
We have two days to sew this thing up.
我需要你再见见巴德
I'm gonna need you to meet with Bud again.
然后，给他一点好处
And, offer him a little incentive.
你要我给他一袋钱？
You want I give him a bag of cash?
不行，太多人盯着呢
No, he's got too much attention on him for that.
我在想也许你可以给他一份工作
I was thinking that maybe you'd offer him a job.
一些好处，你明白我的意思
Something with benefits. If you know what I mean.
马蒂，我正要跟你谈谈
Marty, I've been meaning to talk to you.
我不确信我们用在这个巴德身上的方法是不是可靠
I'm not sure about our strategy on this whole Bud thing.
你从来没质疑过我，任何事
You've never questioned me before. On anything.
从没
Ever.
我知道，我不是说我做不到，只是…
I know and I'm not saying I won't do it. I just...
我摆脱不掉这种感觉…
I can't shake this feeling...
我们改变立场的方式 而现在还要给巴德工作…
The way we've been switching positions, and now offering Bud...
我们只是在做我们一直都在做的事
We're just doing what we always do.
就是这样
That's all.
做我们该做的事情 争取我们该争取的选民
Dancing the dance, Courting the voters.
除了这一次，这次只有一个选民
Except this time, it's only one voter.
一个人
It's one guy.
这就是历史，总统先生
This is history, Mr. President.
以前从未发生过
It's never happened before.
这是全世界都会记住的一刻，永远记住
This is a moment the whole world will remember. Forever.
我明白了
I understand.
我们该怎么办？
What are we about?
赢
Winning.
因为如果我们不能赢的话 你就不能实现你的目标了
Because if we don't win, you can't do what you set out to do.
而你做过的一切，都会不算数
And what you've done, won't matter.
如果我们输了，就都完了
If we don't win, it's all over.
你也完了
And you're over.
巴德！
Bud!
几点了？
What time is it?
迟到了，迟到了 你答应过今天送我上学的
Late. It's late. You promised to take me in today.
好吧！等我几分钟
Okay! Just give me a few minutes.
今天什么日子？
What's today?
算了吧
Forget it.
你能送我吗？
Can you take me, please?
呃，好吧，我们走
Yeah Ye. Let's go.
噢， 老天！
Oh, God!
嗨，等等，莫莉
Hey, wait a minute, Molly.
莫莉！莫莉！
Molly! Molly!
约翰逊先生…约翰逊先生！
Mr. Johnson... Mr. Johnson!
总统想跟你谈谈
The President would like a word with you.
- 总统？ - 是的，先生
- The President? - Yes, sir.
嗨，别那么无聊！
Hey, get a life!
在我被解雇之前我在吉尔摩上班
I used to work at Gilmore before I got laid off.
现在，我在找我能干的活儿
Now, I find work wherever I can.
给人除草，修东西
Mow people's lawns, fixing stuff.
不太容易
Hasn't been easy.
莫莉
Molly.
如果你爸爸能为我说句话的话 我会非常感激
I'd sure appreciate it if your Dad could put in a good word for me at the plant.
谢谢，麦克和埃弗雷特先生的…
Thank you, Michael and Mr. Everett for that...
演讲
presentation.
下一个？
Who's next?
莫莉
Molly.
我想你们都已经认识我爸爸了
I guess you all probably know my dad.
他今天很想来的，但是…
He really wanted to be here today, but...
他有很多重要的事情要做
he had so many important things to do.
他在尽力，但是…
He's doing his best, but...
他不能马上出现在每个地方
he can't be everywhere at once.
自从这事发生以后…
Ever since all this stuff happened...
他真的承担了很大的压力
he's really been under a lot of pressure.
我只是希望你们知道…
I just want you to know that...
他很认真地对待他的责任…
he takes his responsibilities seriously...
他真的很关心穷人…
and that he really cares about helping poor people...
和病人
and sick people.
和那些无助的人
And people that can't help themselves.
我…
My...
我爸爸希望这个国家变得更美好
my dad wants to make this country a better place.
你想过将来吗？巴德
Do you think much about your future?
什么将来？
What future?
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean.
我们都担心我们的晚年
We all worry about the sun down years.
迟早，这些喧闹都会归于沉寂
Sooner or later, all this hoopla is gonna die down.
他们会为我建一个图书馆
They're gonna build me a library.
而你也不过是重新变回到芸芸众生
And you're gonna be just another face in the crowd.
就等着这一天呢
Can't wait.
你得考虑下生活保障了
What you need to think about is security.
我有个朋友…
Now I've got a friend...
可以给你份工作，在大厅里
who might have a job for you. In the lobby business.
就像给人开门的那种？
Like opening doors for people?
你很聪明！
Very astute!
给政治家和支票开门
Open doors to politicians. And their checkbooks.
人们很喜欢你，巴德 他们觉得你是他们中的一员
People really like you, Bud. They feel like you're one of them.
我不是很懂，安迪
I'm not quite following you, Andy.
有时候你会想你一辈子想要什么
Sometimes you gotta figure out what you want in this life.
然后你会想这对你有多重要
Then you have to decide how much it's worth to you.
因为他们会在你的墓碑上写
Because they're gonna put it on your tombstone.
这是你的遗产
It's your legacy.
看看你留下了什么
A measure of what you left behind.
我们…
Are we...
我们能不能说下工作？
are we still talking about the job?
大厅的工作？
The lobby business?
好吧，忘了它吧
Right. Forget that.
一点都不值
It's not worth it.
还有谢谢你
And thank you.
莫莉！
Molly!
你说过只要我想聊聊就找你，对么？
You said that if I ever wanted to talk, right?
热可可
Here's some hot cocoa.
抱歉，我只有脱脂牛奶了
Sorry. All I had was skim milk.
没关系
It's okay.
怎么了？
What's going on?
- 都是我的错 - 什么你的错？
- It's all my fault. - What's your fault?
巴德本来放学后要来接我的
Bud was supposed to meet me after school.
他知道这对我有多重要，但是他喝醉了
He knew how important it was to me. But he got drunk.
他根本没来，我不知道该怎么办！
He never even showed up. I didn't know what else to do!
等等，莫莉，你在说什么？
Wait, Molly, what are you saying?
莫莉？
Molly?
你不接电话吗？
Aren't you gonna get that?
嗯，等我一会儿，待在这儿，我去挂电话
Yeah, give me two seconds. Stay here. I'm gonna get them off the phone.
我再打给你？ 现在不是时候，是的，我知道
Can call you back? This isn't a good time. Yeah, I know.
我知道，你已经告诉我了
I know. You already told me that.
听着，我再打给你？
Look, can I call you back?
莫莉？
Molly?
莫莉！
Molly!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
你想你爸今晚会喝醉吗？
You think your dad might be passed out tonight?
你是说，你会重新投票
Then, you're going to recast your vote.
我猜这不是个秘密了，对吧？
I guess it ain't that much of a secret then, is it?
如果我们想重新创造历史 我们就得打破这个怪圈
If we are to be the exception to history, then we must break the cycle.
人们忘却历史…
For those who do not remember the past...
提醒我下谁在竞选？
Remind me again who's running?
所以，你是说，你仍然…
So, what you're saying is, you're keeping...
都是我的错，巴德本来放学后要来接我
It's all my fault. Bud was supposed to meet me after school.
他知道这对我有多重要，但是他喝醉了
He knew how important this was to me. But he got drunk.
他都没来，我不知道该怎么办！
He didn't even show up. I didn't know what else to do!
莫莉，你在说什么？
Molly, what are you saying?
他没有投票！
He didn't vote!
失踪，你什么意思，她失踪了？
What do you mean, she's missing?
我很抱歉，约翰逊先生，都是我的错
I'm sorry, Mr. Johnson. It's all my fault.
大声说，路易斯！
For crying out loud, Lewis!
你们这些家伙可是保护总统的
You guys guard Presidents.
她太机灵了！
She's smarter!
说说看！
Tell me about it!
这都是些什么？
What is all this?
她在给你回信
She's been answering your mail.
为什么？
For what?
她希望人们以为你很关心他们
She wanted people to think that you cared.
她告诉你的？
She told you that?
约翰逊先生 莫莉有没有什么朋友我们可以联系的？
Does have any friends we should contact?
我不知道
I don't know.
没有，她不交朋友
No, she's not the friend type.
杰德
Jed.
- 杰德？杰德是谁？ - 她喜欢的一个男孩儿
- Jed? Who's Jed? - It's a boy she likes.
她喜欢一个男孩儿？
She likes a boy?
杰德・巴克利，他们一个班的
Jed Barkley. He's in her class.
他有点害羞，但是他们是朋友
He's a little shy, but they're friends.
- 是她告诉你的？ - 是的，先生
- Is she told you that? - Yes, sir.
你知不知道她会去哪儿？
Do you have any idea where she might be going?
呃，我想我知道
Yeah, I'm can guess where she's going.
那告诉我们，我们好去接她，先生
Just tell us where, we'll go pick her up, sir.
她是我女儿，我去接她
She's my daughter. I'll get her myself.
就是这里
This is it.
你要进去？
Sure you wanna go in?
都走了这么远了，不是吗？
Came this far, didn't we?
我在这儿等一会儿，免得你又要回去
I'll wait here awhile. Just in case you want to go home.
我再也不想回去了
I never want to go home.
什么事？
Yes?
我想找拉莉萨・斯塔
I'm looking for Larissa Star.
呃，她搬走了，搬了很久了
Well, she's gone. She's moved out a long time ago.
我看你就是她
I think you're her.
你是杰德？
You Jed?
- 没事，她进去了吗？ - 是的，先生
- It's okay, is she in there? - Yes, sir.
在这儿等着
Wait here.
你长大了！
You're all grown up!
长得像你爸
You look like your dad.
他说我长得像你
He says I look like you.
是吗？那么，你为什么要来？
Does he? So, why did you come here?
你给我写过信，说我可以跟你一起住
You wrote me a letter. You said I could come live with you.
好久以前的事了，宝贝
That was a long time ago, honey.
情况变了
Things have changed.
我快签唱片了
I'm close to getting a record deal.
两个月前我办了场演奏会
I did a gig a couple of months ago.
有人想让我联系一个 有名的纳什维尔制作人
This guy wants to put me in touch with this big time Nashville producer.
所以他会打电话给我的 我还没准备好
So he's gonna call me. I'm not gonna be ready.
我还没准备好 我还有一堆事要做，所以不行
I gotta get ready. There's a lot I gotta do, so I can't do this.
我情况不好，你没看到吗？
I'm not well. Can't you see that?
我会照顾你的，妈妈
I can take care of you, Mom.
我不需要别人照顾我，我不要你在这儿
I don't want anybody to take care of me. I don't want you here.
爸爸！
Dad!
老天，拉莉萨！
Jesus Christ, Larissa!
我不想她看到我这样
I don't want her to see me like this.
莫莉，你去外面，听话？ 出去等我，你出去等我
Molly, you gotta go outside, okay? For me. You got out there and wait.
- 爸爸！ - 出去，快点！
- Dad! - Just outside. Now!
我听说你已经还清债了
I heard you'd finally gotten cleaned up.
谁告诉你的？ 老天，巴德，外面怎么了？
Who told you that? My God, what is going on out there?
很难解释
I can't explain.
你想怎么样，现在出名啦？ 你想来接我？不行！
What are you, famous now? You think you can just come? I can't do this!
- 等等… - 不要！不要！待在那儿
- Wait... - No! No! Come here.
我没疯拉莉萨
I'm not mad Larissa.
站住！我告诉你…
I'm trying to tell you...
我现在不能当妈，不能，后退！我不能…
I can't be a mom right now. I can't. Stay back! I can't...
现在当妈，我不能，我不能
be a mom right now. I can't do it. I can't do it.
说了不见记者的，路易斯
Said no reporters, Lewis.
我只是想跟你谈谈
I just want to talk to you.
我没时间，凯特
I don't have time, Kate.
明晚在无数人面前我要主持一个总统辩论
I'm moderating a Presidential debate tomorrow night in front of a zillion.
我真爱你啊，又让我上电视了…
So as much as I'd love for you to make an ass out of me again on TV...
我得做一些准备
I kinda have some preparing to do.
我得准备下话题
I have to catch up on the issues.
像他们一样！
Like all of them!
巴德
Bud.
我知道选举那晚发生的事
I know what happened election night.
我报道的故事，我只是想确保我知道的是真相
I'm running the story. I just want to make sure I've got my facts right.
酒保说你7：30离开的斯塔林
The bartender claims you left the Starline about 7:30.
对吗？
Is that correct?
是的，小姐
Yes, madam.
你有足够的时间去投票站接莫莉…
Giving you plenty of time to meet at the polling station...
并投下一票…
and cast your vote...
对吧？
right?
我…猜是的
I... guess so.
只是确认下
Just making sure.
我很抱歉，有个东西给你
I'm sorry. I got something for you.
有那么一会儿忘了我是谁
Kinda forgot who I was for a moment.
原谅我了？
Forgive me?
看情况
That depends.
你能帮我吗，今晚帮他？
Can you help me, help him tonight?
我很乐意
I'd love to.
我干两份工，只为了养家糊口
I work two jobs just trying to make ends meet.
去年我的儿子被诊断为…
Last year my son was diagnosed with...
立法者为低收入的艾滋病人更新了主要项目
Law makers renewed the primary programs for low income HIV and AIDS patients.
为了赖安・怀特 一个年轻的艾滋病宣传分子…
Named for Ryan White, a young AIDS activist...
各位晚上好
Good evening everyone.
我们在一个美国小镇为您做现场报道…
We come to you live from a small American town...
一个几个月前从未听说过的小镇
a town most of us had never heard of just a few weeks ago.
一个在地图上找不到的小镇…
A town you couldn't find on the map...
因为以前地图上 没有新墨西哥州的德士古镇
because Texico, New Mexico, wasn't on the map.
但是现在有了
But it's on the map now.
全世界都在关注这个镇上历史性的一刻
The whole world has descended on this town for an historic event.
一个与众不同的政治辩论
A political debate unlike any other.
明天早上，埃里斯特・巴德・约翰逊…
Tomorrow morning, Earnest Bud Johnson...
将会去投票站做出他的选择
will walk into a voting booth and make a choice.
他的选择将影响我们的未来
And his choice will affect our lives for generations to come.
赌注不能再高了，你怎么看？
The stakes could not be higher. What do you expect?
我在想，亚伦，我们国父们的意愿是什么
I wonder, Aaron, what the founding fathers would make of all this.
他们是感到羞辱，还是会欢呼雀跃？
Would they be mortified, or would they be jumping for joy?
有种感觉告诉我现在在某个地方…
Something tells me that somewhere right now...
富兰克林和杰弗逊正在看着我们并朝我们微笑
Franklin and Jefferson are looking down and smiling.
微笑还是嘲笑？
Smiling or laughing?
我不知道是不是在微笑
I don't know if they're smiling.
约翰逊可不是他们想要的 来选美国总统的人
That's not exactly who they had in mind for picking the President of the USA.
我们关注的这个人 就我来看的话，还是一团糊涂
We're sending someone out there who really is, as far as, we can tell lost.
他能突然找到感觉吗，在今晚的台上…
Can he find himself suddenly, tonight on this stage...
还是看起来像是个马戏团的小丑？
Or is he going to look like a rodeo clown down there?
今晚，全国都在观看 我们和您一同关注
Tonight, the whole country is watching and we watch with you.
我想吐
I'm gonna puke.
巴德，看着我，看着我
Bud, look at me. Look at me.
好好表现，你会很棒的
Just be yourself. You're gonna be great.
嗨，爸爸记得，不要说粗话！好吗？
Hey, remember dad. No cussing! Okay?
- 好的 - 好
- Fine. - Fine.
约翰逊先生，还有一分钟
Mr. Johnson, one minute, please.
好运！
Good luck!
现在开始
And so we begin.
大家都就座了，我们就去舞台上…
The crowd has settled down and we go to the stage...
看看据说是…
for what promises to be...
美国政治史上最独特的一幕
one of the most unique moments in American political history.
总统先生，格林利夫先生…
Mr. President, Mr. Greenleaf...
我很感谢你们的款待，非常有意思
I'd like to thank you for your hospitality. It's been real interesting.
我曾说过一些原非本意的话
I've said a lot of thing I didn't mean.
你们也都做出了很多承诺…
And you both made a lot of promises...
那些不会实现的承诺
you probably won't be able to keep.
老实说，过去的十天就像是个奇怪的梦
To be honest, the last 10 days have felt like a weird dream.
有些好笑的东西，已经都不好笑
What was once kinda funny, isn't anymore.
报纸上都说，我…
From what I've read, I've...
呃，我让整个美国都捏了一把汗
well, I've scared the hell out of America.
我知道整个世界都在看着我们 或许还在嘲笑
I know that the world is watching, maybe even laughing.
电视上的人说…
People on my own TV, are saying...
美国，无论如何，值得拥有这一刻
that America, somehow, deserves this moment.
想想那是指我吧
Guess that means me.
我不能说我的一生有多么重要
I can't say that I've been much of anything most of my life.
就像一路走来到达某一处…
It's sorta like somewhere along the way...
我仔细回想 我没有过很大的梦想
I checked out and it's not like I had big dreams to begin with.
但我曾经也有过追求
But I had something once.
有过类似信念或者希望，不管怎样…
I had something close to faith or hope or whatever...
任何你们用来描绘美好生活的词
whatever word you want to use for how good life could be.
但是，时间开始流逝，然后突然…
But then, the years start moving quicker and all of a sudden...
每个人都幸福满满…
what's going good out there for every else...
但你却不是
isn't going so good for you.
但是，今晚我感觉…
But, tonight I feel...
很难堪
embarrassed.
我也有过很多很多的机会
I've had my chances, more than most.
我生长的这个国家…
I've grown up in a country where...
如果我这一生多做点正事 而不是游荡酗酒的话…
if I decided to do more with my life than just drift and drink...
那么我也可能站在…
that I could be standing where...
你们今晚所站的位置
where maybe you stand tonight.
然而，我随意索取却毫无贡献
Instead, I've taken freely and I've given nothing.
我很惭愧在我的…
I'm ashamed in front of my...
女儿面前
daughter.
还有我的国家面前
And my country.
我从没有付出或者牺牲过
I've never served or sacrificed.
要求我做的也都是些简单的事情，比如…
The only heavy lifting I've been asked is simple stuff, like...
集中精力，投票…
pay attention. Vote...
为了美国能有一个…
For America has a...
如果美国今晚真有一个敌人的话 我想那是我
if America has a true enemy tonight, I guess it's me.
今晚，一个浪荡子 将要在两位精英中做出选择
Tonight a below average man is going to choose between two exceptional men.
明天，一个人的投票将会改变一切…
Tomorrow, one man's vote is going to make a difference...
＂因为明天我们将会有一名总统
"Cause tomorrow we're gonna have a President.
不只是为了填满华盛顿的位置
And not just someone to fill a chair in Washington.
我们需要一个不光只会演说的人
We need someone who's bigger than their speeches.
而是那种我们在学校就学习到的总统
The kind of President we learned about in school.
美国需要一个伟大的思想家
America needs a big thinker.
你们知道的，像个巨人那样，真的
You know, like a giant, really.
一个能真正解决问题的人
Someone who has the good sense to get in front of our problems.
一个用智慧带领我们到达…
Somebody who has the wisdom to lead to us a place...
和平之地的人
where we're at peace with ourselves and the world.
为了记录，我希望你们…
And just for the record, I want you both...
我希望你们知道我很慎重地在做选择
I want you both to know that I think a hella lot of you.
今晚，我将为我素未谋面的人发言…
Tonight, I am going to speak for people I have never met...
他们的来信不可思议地触动了我
whose letters touched me in a way I didn't think was possible.
我的第一个问题来自…
My first question comes from...
肯塔基州，亨德逊的皮特・曼利斯
Peter Manthis, in Henderson, Kentucky.
＂亲爱的约翰逊先生…
"Dear Mr. Johnson...
我妻子和我有三个小女儿
my wife and I have three little girls.
我们都打两份工来养家糊口
We both work two jobs just trying to make ends meet.
但是几周前，我们做不到了”
And some weeks, we don't make it."
＂当你努力工作但仍不能养活全家的时候…
"When you work hard and you still can't take care of your family...
作为一个家庭支柱，作为一个男人 你会开始质疑你自己
you start to question yourself as a provider, as a man.
我知道我就是这样一个人 我为我的国家努力工作，我也很骄傲
I know I am one. I fought for my country and I'm proud of it.
但是我不敢想 要是有个孩子生病了该怎么办
But it scares me to think about what would happen if one of my kids got sick.
＂你能不能问问候选人 如果我们是世界上最富有的国家…
"Can you ask the candidates, if we are richest country in the world...
为什么还有很多人像我一样不能生存呢？＂
how come some many of us can barely afford to live here?"
如果可以的话我先回答吧，格林利夫先生
I'd like to take that one first, if I might, Mr. Greenleaf.
请吧，总统先生
Answer, Mr. President.
巴德，首先我想说 我很欣赏你的深思
Bud, I'd first like to say, how much I appreciate your thoughtfulness.
谢谢观赏！